<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Yelena Strokin &#8211; Cooking Melangery</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/melangery/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>from sauté to soufflé</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 22:46:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cropped-Untitled-1-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Yelena Strokin &#8211; Cooking Melangery</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Homemade Bialys with Goat Cheese and Onions</title>
		<link>/2023/06/homemade-bialys-with-goat-cheese-and-onions.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 22:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bialys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breakfas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goat Cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Homemade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[onions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poppy seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scallions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5568</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Baking sweet or savory breads &#8211; its an act of creation. Bread literally grows from your hands. You bring the dormant yeast to life, knead the flour into the dough, nature it, care for it, and shape it into a loaf, rolls, or braid it, then bake it until its golden brown and smooth outside, chewy and tasty inside. Bread baking is one of the most ancient, most elemental rituals. Before there were molds, loaves were usually round. Before there were ovens, dough was flattened for easier cooking. Today, round and flat loaves are still popular, but bread come in all shapes and sizes, and from all kind of grains. Sardinian bakers make very thin crackling rounds called “fogli di music” (sheets of music); from France we get long, crusty baguettes; in Mexico tortillas are most popular; and the Portuguese are known for their light, puffy sweet bread.&#160; Every bread has a unique history. Originally from Poland, traditionally the bialys are made with sauté onions and poppy seeds. But if you like to indulge yourself, add soft goat cheese on a top and fresh scallions in the dough. Bialys are great toasted with butter or a schemer with cream cheese. [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How A Balanced Diet Can Prevent Obesity</title>
		<link>/2023/06/how-a-balanced-diet-can-prevent-obesity.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 01:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[article]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=7404</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Even the latest med technology can&#8217;t completely cure one of the nation&#8217;s most urgent health problems: obesity. More than 42% of American adults are obese, with rates steadily growing. That&#8217;s over 4 out of 10 people—significantly higher than a decade ago, when no state had an adult obesity rate over 35%. Yet while this problem is multifactored and will take many interdisciplinary solutions to solve completely, there is one simple, vital step almost everyone can take to lower their risk: a balanced diet. But why exactly is this a vital strategy for you to adopt? Read on to learn more about what obesity is, how it impacts your health—and how a balanced diet can help mitigate the effects of this condition. Obesity and your health Obesity is the excess of fat. Though often confused with being overweight, the body mass index (BMI) classification system—which determines how your weight measures compared to your height—shows a significant difference between overweight vs obesity. You&#8217;re considered overweight or pre-obese if you have a BMI of 25 to 29.9, and obese if you reach a BMI of 30. Though both overweight and obese individuals risk developing heart disease, high blood pressure, and diabetes, obesity is more likely to [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Connection between a tasty pizza and overcoming depression.</title>
		<link>/2022/01/connection-between-a-tasty-pizza-and-overcoming-depression.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 23:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[article]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pizza]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=7353</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;re in the mood for a little lighthearted reading, we thought we&#8217;d share with you this humorous and informative piece on the connection between pizza and depression. It&#8217;s worth a read — we guarantee that even if you&#8217;re not feeling depressed, it&#8217;ll leave you feeling better than ever! Ok, now let&#8217;s get serious for a second:&#160;overcoming depression is extremely difficult. There are many things to consider, such as finding safe ways to express your emotions and thoughts, trying new activities, finding accountability partners who will positively influence your recovery process&#8230; But whatever your journey entails or wherever it may lead, don&#8217;t forget that people love and support you just as much as they always have. You&#8217;re not alone. What&#8217;s the connection between a tasty pizza and overcoming depression? Psychiatrist and psychoanalyst Irvin D. Yalom, MD, wrote Love&#8217;s Executioner: The Myth of the Self-Absorbed Adult. He presents his take on &#8220;rebellious children&#8221; about adults who have trouble connecting with others in this book. He says that some people, such as rebels and psychopaths, use food to cope with their anxieties and stressors. Therefore Dr. Yalom believes that when depressed people eat pizza, they show signs of self-soothing behavior. We couldn&#8217;t [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 Unexpected Cooking Ingredients You Should Have On Hand In Your Kitchen</title>
		<link>/2022/01/7-unexpected-cooking-ingredients-you-should-have-on-hand-in-your-kitchen.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 16:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cofee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sugar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=7379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cooking is an activity that you will get better at over time. Some cooks will struggle with portion size and cooking times when they first start out; however, others will take to the practice like a duck to water. This does not mean that you cannot continue to improve though. The ingredients you use in your recipes can really make a difference, and sometimes it pays to go off the beaten path. If you want your next meals to taste unique, consider having some of these unexpected ingredients to hand in your kitchen. Sugar Sugar is an obvious staple for most bakers, although, you will still find this ingredient useful when cooking up some savory dishes. When cooking something with vegetables, you will find that these ingredients contain their own natural sweetness. This helps to cut out some of the acidity in some meals, especially ones that are heavy on oil or vinegar. However, not every dish will require enough vegetables to do the job. Therefore, you may find it beneficial to add a pinch of sugar to your bolognese or curry sauces to give them a bit more flavor. Coffee On the topic of pasta dishes, there are two [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Launching A Mobile Cocktail Bar: Practical Tips For Entrepreneurial Mixologists </title>
		<link>/2022/01/launching-a-mobile-cocktail-bar-practical-tips-for-entrepreneurial-mixologists.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[article]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cocktail bar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[practical tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=7367</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For passionate cocktail lovers, launching your own bar is the ultimate dream. However, high start-up costs and an uncertain economy might make it hard for you to get started. Thankfully, there are ways to reduce the initial cost and future proof your business. One great solution is to consider launching a mobile cocktail bar.&#160; Mobile cocktail bars can be housed in the back of trucks or on trailers and can easily be launched at events such as weddings and music festivals or in open spaces to attract crowds of party-lovers. Whatever you intend to do with your mobile cocktail bar, you need to make sure that you do it right if you want to succeed.&#160; That’s why we’ve put together this list of practical tips to help you get your mobile cocktail bar off to an amazing start! Create A Plan Mobile cocktail bars come in all shapes and sizes, so the first step is to create a plan. Think about who you want to attract, where you plan to host events and what you want to offer. Some mobile cocktail bars serve food, while others have a limited menu of speciality cocktails based around one specific alcohol. Whatever you [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Balanced Diet: What Is It and How to Achieve It?</title>
		<link>/2021/06/balanced-diet-what-is-it-and-how-to-achieve-it.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 23:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[article]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cooking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=7371</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A balanced diet is a diet that includes specific amounts and proportions of different types of food so that requirements for calories, protein, minerals, vitamins, and replacement nutrients are adequate, and small amounts of additional nutrients are retained to support survival during brief periods of leanness. Additionally, a balanced diet should provide bioactive phytochemicals with positive health benefits, such as fiber, antioxidants, and nutraceuticals. A balanced diet should contain approximately 60-70% of total calories from carbohydrates, 10-12% from protein, and 20-25% from fat. You should check food recipes. Health benefits of a balanced diet If you want to eat healthy, you should know all of the benefits for your body and mind. If you choose a balanced diet, that helps you increase energy, improves your body work, strengthens your immune system and other great things. Other big advantages are meeting your nutritional needs. A varied, balanced diet provides the nutrients you need to prevent symptoms of deficiency. Prevent and treat certain diseases. Eating a healthy diet can reduce the risk of certain diseases, such as diabetes, cancer and heart disease. It also helps treat diabetes and high blood pressure. Following a special diet can relieve symptoms and help you better [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fried Brown Rice with Vegetables &#038; Eggs</title>
		<link>/2021/04/fried-brown-rice-with-vegetables-eggs.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 01:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brown Rice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carrots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Herbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Side Dish]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5792</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rice is a staple food throughout much of China and Asia and other places. White and brown plain boiled rice is a useful accompaniment that goes well with a wide variety of dishes, it is easy to combine rice with vegetables, eggs and a range of flavorings and spices to create a rather more special meal. There are many versions of this dish, all of which make use of leftover rice. Ingredients vary according to what is in season. Make sure the rice is cold before attempting to fry it, as warm rice will become soggy. Use rice with a fairly firm texture. Ideally, raw rice should be soaked in water for a short time before cooking.]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Healthy Recipes for a Spring Cleanse</title>
		<link>/2021/02/healthy-recipes-for-a-spring-cleanse.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 22:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salads]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=7284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Easy Steps for a Happy Gut Today, we know that our gut flora, a microbiome population as it is also known as, has a huge impact on our health and our risk of disease. In fact, leading researchers in the field say they can get much more information about your health from assessing your gut flora than some other tests. Each one of us is host to about a pound-and-a-half of gut bacteria made up of over 600 different bacterial families (with each family often having dozens of bacterial strains). The more diverse our gut bacteria population is, the better for our health. A small and limited variety of gut bacteria increases the risk of autoimmune diseases, cancer, heart disease, diabetes, multiple sclerosis, fibromyalgia and obesity. There are several ways to improve the makeup of your gut flora. Read on to find out more. A second brain Because some gut bacteria affect the production of neurotransmitters in the brain, the composition of our gut bacteria also has an effect on our mood, which has a knock-on effect on conditions such as depression and anxiety, to name just a couple.  Inflammation caused by allergies or food intolerances can also affect gut [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zucchini Bread with Mint &#038; Pecans</title>
		<link>/2020/12/zucchini-bread-with-mint-pecans.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:11:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cakes, Tarts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pecan Nuts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raisins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanilla extract]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whole wheat flour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zucchini]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5279</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Line a basket or a pretty dish with a napkin and fill it with breakfast bakes &#8211; hot, tender, and a little sweet. Hearty and robust or delicate cake-like, all slices of quick bread have a place on the morning table. Chunky jams and preserves go well with full-flavored bakes, while the more subtle ones need only sweet butter, a little crème fraîche, or perhaps a spoonful of jelly. Some breads, such as those filled with berries, need no accompaniment at all. Quick breads are made from the same type of batter as muffins. They share the same uneven, sometimes cake-like crumb. They are breads usually feel with nuts and cranberries at Christmas, pumpkin puree near Thanksgiving, and zucchini at summer&#8217;s end when the garden is overrun with the squash. Quick breads very often benefit from being made a day ahead and wrapped tightly in foil to mellow their flavor, but I never can wait that long-) Inspired by: &#8220;Ancient Grains for Modern Meals&#8221; by Maria Speck]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gluten-Free Brownies with Teff Flour (Vegan, Dairy-Free)</title>
		<link>/2020/08/gluten-free-brownies-with-teff-flour-vegan-dairy-free.html</link>
					<comments>/2020/08/gluten-free-brownies-with-teff-flour-vegan-dairy-free.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 17:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Other Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avocado oil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brownies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flax Seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gluten-free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rose petals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=6596</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Using ancient flours and grains while cooking allows you to incorporate new flavors and health factors into your recipe. Flours from so long ago come with a slew of health benefits that the recipe would be missing if you had used regular flour. Teff flour, an ancient flour stemming from Ethiopia, is a gluten-free alternative that is starting to become more widely used. Teff is delicious, hearty, and packed with ancient health benefits Because teff is gluten-free, it is an incredible substitute for those with celiac disease or any other form of gluten sensitivity. Even without sensitivities to gluten, you may still find improvements in your digestion of this flour. typical gluten in a normal body creates inflammation at a low-level in your body, so the switch to a gluten-free flour may have you find unexpected relief. Another huge positive of teff flour is its natural abundance of fiber. Average teff flour can contain up to five times the amount of fiber typically found in flour, further promoting the health benefits of using teff over typical flour. The extra fiber is great for promoting digestive regularity, as well as helping to clear your digestive tract of toxins and food waste. [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/08/gluten-free-brownies-with-teff-flour-vegan-dairy-free.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rye Sourdough Bread with Raisins</title>
		<link>/2020/05/rye-sourdough-bread-with-raisins.html</link>
					<comments>/2020/05/rye-sourdough-bread-with-raisins.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 20:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Homemade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raisins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rye flour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sourdough]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here are some interesting thoughts where the sourdough came from one of my vintage books by Jeff Smith “The Frugal Gourmet Cooks American”. “Sourdough is probably the oldest form of “raised” or “leavened” bread that we know. While the Egyptians are generally given credit for baking the first raised bread, we must also remember that their claim to this fame occurred just after the Jews had fled Egypt, leaving their leavening behind. They were taught to bake unleavened loaves of bread in the desert. Most likely from the historical events that it was the Jews who brought a wild leavening from the desert, a sourdough, into Egypt, and the Hebrew people taught the Egyptians how to bake raised bread in the first place. In any case, we are all familiar with the biblical lines about a little leaven leavening the whole. The Bible is referring to sourdough, and we have been using these wild yeast forms ever since. There is some evidence that Columbus brought a sourdough starter with him on the ships when he set out for the New World. In the time of Columbus, sourdough was the only kind of yeast available. It was used in this country [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/05/rye-sourdough-bread-with-raisins.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazing Breads that Anyone can Bake</title>
		<link>/2020/03/amazing-breads-that-anyone-can-bake.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 18:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sandwich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whole wheat flour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yeast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=7240</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s a staple in homes across our wide, wonderful world. You toast it. You send it to school in your kids’ lunchboxes. You slap whatever culinary delights tickle your fancy on it, to make a complete meal in record time. Bread truly is an incredible, versatile food. Did you ever consider that you could bake it yourself?&#160; If your answer is &#8220;no&#8221;, that you probobly have some reasons for it. It takes too much time. It’s too complicated. It’s too expensive. This article is here to open your eyes to a new world of delicious possibilities.  You see, with bread becoming a mainstay in many global diets, the laws of supply and demand are doing what they do. Take a stroll down the bread aisle, grab two bags of bread, and you’ll see what I mean. As a community, we eat so much bread that companies are forced to use mass production lines to keep up.&#160; If you want anything more specialized than factory-produced bread, you’ve got to go to the bakery. The thing is, these types of bread are priced as specialty items, too. You can get something handmade if you’re willing to pay extra.&#160; If you’re willing to [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Challah</title>
		<link>/2020/03/challah.html</link>
					<comments>/2020/03/challah.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 02:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Challah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5882</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I always think of challah as Eastern European brioche. It&#8217;s a wonderful golden egg-and-butter bread with a texture only slightly tighter then brioche. Braided challah was very popular at our house back in Russia and I like to keep this tradition and make some weekends and holidays extra special by baking challah myself.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/03/challah.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicken of the Woods Cream of Mushroom Soup</title>
		<link>/2019/10/chicken-of-the-woods-cream-of-mushroom-soup.html</link>
					<comments>/2019/10/chicken-of-the-woods-cream-of-mushroom-soup.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 01:27:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetable and Grain Soups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buckwheat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicken of the woods mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foraging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wild]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is a hearty soup that captures the flavor of the Chicken of the woods. It goes best with a full-bodied Zinfandel for a midday lunch! Laetiporus sulphureous known as Chicken-of-the-Woods The common name of this a fungus derives from the fact that, when cooked, this mushroom has the texture of fresh chicken breast. The fungus is one of a larger group of fungi known as polypores &#8211; similar to boletes in that the underside of the cap is composed of pores rather than gills. In most cases polyphonies are inedible because of their woody texture. Some, however, are quite good to eat, and the chicken of the woods is among the best known. It is also known as the sulfur mushroom because the underside of the cap is a bright yellow color. The top side is red-orange, which makes it very easy to identify. These fungi can be seen growing out of fallen and rotting trees from summer to late fall. Older specimens take a long time to cook because of their woody texture. Younger specimens take just a short time to make them soft and chewable. The part of the fungus farthest from the base is the most [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/10/chicken-of-the-woods-cream-of-mushroom-soup.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Maple Roasted Brussels Sprouts with Cumin-Scented Quinoa &#038; Pecans</title>
		<link>/2019/09/maple-roasted-brussels-sprouts-with-cumin-scented-quinoa-pecans.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 01:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brussels Sprouts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cilantro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dinner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gluten-free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maple syrup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pecan Nuts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pomegranate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quinoa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roasted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Side Dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5283</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The crunchiness and superb simplicity of roasted Brussel sprouts are underrated. They are a delicacy. Combine this humble vegetable with ancient quinoa and wait for those flavors to merge into a divine union. Serve with pan-fried fish or grilled chicken.]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Will the Instant Pot be Your New Best Friend in the Kitchen?</title>
		<link>/2019/08/will-the-instant-pot-be-your-new-best-friend-in-the-kitchen.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 15:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=7221</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cooking is a fundamental part of life but is also something that people the world over enjoy doing. Some people train for years to become a chef, while others are more than happy whipping up something in their kitchen to feed the family. Whether or not you are a professional chef, there are a number of different pieces of equipment that are vital to the success of any kitchen. Cooking pots and pans come in all shapes and sizes, with some having been developed to cater for a specific type of cooking. For example, a slow cooker is a great way to slowly cook a Sunday roast, but you wouldn’t use it to boil a couple of eggs or to make a cake. The same goes for a pressure cooker. It’s a great way to cook meat so that it stays soft and tender, but it’s going to be much use for you if you are planning to cook some pasta. Having all of these different pots takes up a lot of space in your kitchen, and if your home isn’t so large, you could very easily find yourself being crowded out of your kitchen by the very pots and [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Baked Oat Squares with Flax Seeds, Pecans and Berries</title>
		<link>/2019/04/baked-oat-squares-with-flax-seeds-pecans-and-berries.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[egg free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flax Seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pecan Nuts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soy free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanilla extract]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5563</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This recipe is perfectly sweet, filled with oats, crunchy nuts, flax seeds, fresh berries, and fragrant vanilla, and delicious served cold on a next day. A healthy make-ahead breakfast for busy mornings. To grind the flax seeds, pour it into a blender and blend it for 3-5 minutes or until it&#8217;s ground to your liking. For the small amount, you can grind the flax seeds using a coffee grinder.]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
