<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Pasta, Rice, Grains &#8211; Cooking Melangery</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/pasta-rice-grains/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>from sauté to soufflé</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 22:53:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cropped-Untitled-1-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Pasta, Rice, Grains &#8211; Cooking Melangery</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Fried Brown Rice with Vegetables &#038; Eggs</title>
		<link>/2021/04/fried-brown-rice-with-vegetables-eggs.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 01:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brown Rice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carrots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Herbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Side Dish]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5792</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rice is a staple food throughout much of China and Asia and other places. White and brown plain boiled rice is a useful accompaniment that goes well with a wide variety of dishes, it is easy to combine rice with vegetables, eggs and a range of flavorings and spices to create a rather more special meal. There are many versions of this dish, all of which make use of leftover rice. Ingredients vary according to what is in season. Make sure the rice is cold before attempting to fry it, as warm rice will become soggy. Use rice with a fairly firm texture. Ideally, raw rice should be soaked in water for a short time before cooking.]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicken of the Woods Cream of Mushroom Soup</title>
		<link>/2019/10/chicken-of-the-woods-cream-of-mushroom-soup.html</link>
					<comments>/2019/10/chicken-of-the-woods-cream-of-mushroom-soup.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 01:27:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetable and Grain Soups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buckwheat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicken of the woods mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foraging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wild]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is a hearty soup that captures the flavor of the Chicken of the woods. It goes best with a full-bodied Zinfandel for a midday lunch! Laetiporus sulphureous known as Chicken-of-the-Woods The common name of this a fungus derives from the fact that, when cooked, this mushroom has the texture of fresh chicken breast. The fungus is one of a larger group of fungi known as polypores &#8211; similar to boletes in that the underside of the cap is composed of pores rather than gills. In most cases polyphonies are inedible because of their woody texture. Some, however, are quite good to eat, and the chicken of the woods is among the best known. It is also known as the sulfur mushroom because the underside of the cap is a bright yellow color. The top side is red-orange, which makes it very easy to identify. These fungi can be seen growing out of fallen and rotting trees from summer to late fall. Older specimens take a long time to cook because of their woody texture. Younger specimens take just a short time to make them soft and chewable. The part of the fungus farthest from the base is the most [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/10/chicken-of-the-woods-cream-of-mushroom-soup.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Maple Roasted Brussels Sprouts with Cumin-Scented Quinoa &#038; Pecans</title>
		<link>/2019/09/maple-roasted-brussels-sprouts-with-cumin-scented-quinoa-pecans.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 01:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brussels Sprouts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cilantro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dinner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gluten-free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maple syrup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pecan Nuts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pomegranate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quinoa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roasted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Side Dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5283</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The crunchiness and superb simplicity of roasted Brussel sprouts are underrated. They are a delicacy. Combine this humble vegetable with ancient quinoa and wait for those flavors to merge into a divine union. Serve with pan-fried fish or grilled chicken.]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Baked Oat Squares with Flax Seeds, Pecans and Berries</title>
		<link>/2019/04/baked-oat-squares-with-flax-seeds-pecans-and-berries.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[egg free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flax Seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pecan Nuts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soy free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanilla extract]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5563</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This recipe is perfectly sweet, filled with oats, crunchy nuts, flax seeds, fresh berries, and fragrant vanilla, and delicious served cold on a next day. A healthy make-ahead breakfast for busy mornings. To grind the flax seeds, pour it into a blender and blend it for 3-5 minutes or until it&#8217;s ground to your liking. For the small amount, you can grind the flax seeds using a coffee grinder.]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amaranth &#038; Steel Cut Oats Porridge with Nuts &#038; Fruits</title>
		<link>/2019/01/amaranth-steel-cut-oats-porridge-with-nuts-fruits.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[almond butter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Almond milk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amaranth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chia seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flax Seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hemp seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steel cut oats]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=4821</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A valuable source of fiber and nutrients, grains have long been a vital part of man&#8217;s diet. They have been ground into flour for baking since ancient times, and for just as long have been eaten as a hot cereal &#8211; also called mush or gruel. Grains are the dried seeds of grass-like plans. The most familiar are wheat, rice, oats, corn, rye, barley, buckwheat, and millet. All can be eaten hot as a cereal by boiling them. Oats are usually steamed to soften them and then rolled into flaky particles. The only difference between old-fashioned and quick oats is the thickness and size of the flakes. Steel-cut oats, also called Scotch or Irish oatmeal, are small-cut oat grains with a nuttier flavor then rolled oats. I like to use them a lot for my porridges. Amaranth (amaranthus caudatus) is a gluten-free, pseudo-cereal seed with an earthy, grassy flavor, similar to beets. Amaranth seeds can be cooked into porridge, ground into flour, popped or flaked. As a complete protein (containing 18 amino acids), amaranth was an energizing staple for the Aztecs and Mayans who used it to make tortillas, atole and sweets. This tiny seed is a rich source of calcium, iron, [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy Thanksgiving Everybody! Einkorn Risotto with sautéed Mushrooms &#038; Fresh Herbs</title>
		<link>/2018/11/happy-thanksgiving-everybody-einkorn-risotto-with-sauteed-mushrooms-fresh-herbs.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 22:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Butter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dinner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[einkorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fresh herbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Risotto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thanksgiving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thyme]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=3468</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Today we have gathered and we see that the cycles of life continue. We have been given the duty to live in balance and harmony with each other and all living things. So now, we bring our minds together as one as we give greetings and thanks to each other as People. Now our minds are one. We give thanks to all the Waters of the world for quenching our thirst and providing us with strength. Water is life. We know its power in many forms— waterfalls and rain, mists and streams, rivers and oceans. With one mind, we send greetings and thanks to the spirit of Water. Now our minds are one. Now we turn our thoughts to the Creator, or Great Spirit, and send greetings and thanks for all the gifts of Creation. Everything we need to live a good life is here on this Mother Earth. For all the love that is still around us, we gather our minds together as one and send our choicest words of greetings and thanks to the Creator. Now our minds are one.” These words of Thanksgiving come to us from the Native people are known as the Iroquois or Six [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Autumn Recipe with Roasted Vegetables, Lima Beans &#038; Buckwheat- Florida Trip (Part Two)</title>
		<link>/2018/11/autumn-recipe-with-roasted-vegetables-lima-beans-buckwheat-florida-trip-part-two.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 22:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Autumn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buckwheat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cauliflower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lima beans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roasted pumpkin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=3767</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I had some lovely time with my dear friends and clients in Winter Park, Florida at the beginning of September. My photography exhibition was taking place at AXIOM gallery while I visited Jeff and Bryan (the owners of The Ancient Olive store) at the same time. They were the first people who loved my still life art photography and we have worked together on branding for their stores. I was so happy to see their shopping bags, business cards and company stationery beautified by my art. Jeffrey and Bryan are very dear to me and finally, we got to meet and spend some time together. There is so much to do in Winter Park, but the town’s most attractive place is their store. The Ancient Olive carries a boutique assortment of amazing cheeses, jams, mustards, sauces, oils, and vinegar. The store itself is absolutely lovely and that extends to the people who work there. I have tasted many delicious gourmet foods my only regret was having an only small suitcase with me 😊 Regardless, my family was happy with the gifts from the shop, the only problem &#8211; it was all gone in no time-)) I have created this recipe [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Homemade Hummus Made with Dried Chickpeas</title>
		<link>/2015/03/homemade-hummus-made-with-dry-chickpeas.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/03/homemade-hummus-made-with-dry-chickpeas.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 22:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chickpeas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Extra virgin Olive Oil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Herbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hummus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sesame seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tahini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zahter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/03/12/homemade-hummus-made-with-dry-chickpeas/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This dish already is thousands of years old. When I traveled through the Middle East I have tried hummus from street food carts and in fancy restaurants. Each hummus master would tell you a story of his unique recipe passed from generation to generation, but he would not reveal the recipe to anyone, of course. If hummus is made correctly, it is very pleasant and even addictive vegetarian dish. Some people say it helps to lower cholesterol. Hummus should never be cooked using canned chickpeas. Cooked chickpeas must be thoroughly peeled before use. Olive oil quality is crucial for hummus. If you’ve got a bottle of fancy olive oil and decided to make your own hummus, this would be a good reason to open it.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/03/homemade-hummus-made-with-dry-chickpeas.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Homemade Beet Pasta &#038; SAVORA GIVEAWAY</title>
		<link>/2014/10/homemade-beet-pasta-savora-giveaway.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/10/homemade-beet-pasta-savora-giveaway.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 09:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bell pepper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Giveaway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parmesan cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roasted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Savora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White Wine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/10/31/homemade-beet-pasta-savora-giveaway/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is a colorful pasta, made from roasted beets with a sweet aftertaste and a lovely bright color that marries best with cheese sauce and fresh herbs that show off its beauty.&#160;Small beets will impart magenta color; larger beets will impart a darker, almost purplish color. Some of the colors will inevitably leach out into the water, but the cooked pasta will still be quite bright. Since I have redesigned my kitchen and focused on every tiny detail that went into it, now I have another difficult task ahead of me. I need to update all of the contents of my kitchen. You probably saw the beautiful containers that I posted about, but now I&#8217;m on a mission to find functional, yet beautiful appliances that will further enhance the beauty (and purposefulness) of my kitchen. Here&#8217;s where Savora line comes in. I already had a few pieces from them that I enjoyed, but these next ones are true keepers. The colander just looks dazzling on my kitchen, especially when I add the colorful fruits, vegetables or pasta to it. The pizza wheel is similar to a Santoku knife since its blade has killed along the sides that create air pockets [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/10/homemade-beet-pasta-savora-giveaway.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>70</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: &#8220;Grechnevay Kasha&#8221; &#8211; Buckwheat with Dried Mushrooms, Pumpkin &#038; Onion</title>
		<link>/2014/10/russian-monday-grechnevay-kasha.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/10/russian-monday-grechnevay-kasha.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 07:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Main Dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buckwheat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carrots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Main dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Onion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Porridge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pumpkin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Side Dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/10/27/russian-monday-grechnevay-kasha/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Good hearty buckwheat kasha is a serious matter. It’s a thing in itself crowning the whole of Russian cuisine. It requires a responsible and thorough approach when cooking with it, but the rewards are hundredfold. You will appreciate it when, after one helping of kasha, you will reach out for the second one. Today’s recipe is the old inherited one, from along time ago used in Russia &#8211; buckwheat with wild mushrooms. On its own, buckwheat porridge is very tasty and healthy, but with the addition of cooked mushrooms you won’t be able to pull yourself away from it. This recipe is not just to everyone’s liking, but it’s also vegetarian, gluten free and dairy free (unless you serve it with sour cream). Fresh mushrooms can also be used, but buckwheat will be the aroma of the dish and it is the best with the dried ones. For more Russian recipes, visit Russian Cuisine page.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/10/russian-monday-grechnevay-kasha.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Purple Autumn: Black Lentil Stew with Beets &#038; Fig Balsamic Vinegar</title>
		<link>/2014/10/purple-autumn-black-lentil-stew-with.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/10/purple-autumn-black-lentil-stew-with.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 20:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Autumn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Black Beluga Lentil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carrots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dinner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gluten free diet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Purple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Purple Potato]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Red Onion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/10/08/purple-autumn-black-lentil-stew-wi/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What a beautiful evening it is outside tonight as I write this! The air is still warm enough to be comfortable, but a cool breeze is coaxing the still-vibrant summer vines to dance tonight under the almost full moon. Katydids and crickets are busy making &#8220;a little night music&#8221; while toads, from tiny to plump, jump from sidewalk to lawn, entertaining our little dog as my husband I stroll with her on our evening walk. Fall is coming, with farms across the Bucks county countryside boasting an abundance of orange pumpkins, yellow and green gourds, rosy apples, and rich russet Indian corn. Maple trees along our picturesque country roads decorate fields and farms with deepest pink and garnet. And for a couple of weeks every October, the woods behind our houses look painted over completely in gold with leaves both fallen and still clinging to the sassafras trees. The color that has caught Yelena&#8217;s artist eye this autumn, however, is royal purple. She&#8217;s found it all over our garden, from the exotic Passionflowers and high summer&#8217;s Cleomes and Persian Shield, to our Hyacinth beans; the towering vine laden with gorgeous violet pods. Autumn&#8217;s purple produce has also found its way [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/10/purple-autumn-black-lentil-stew-with.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Warm Mediterranean Farro Salad with Mushrooms</title>
		<link>/2014/09/mediterranean-warm-farro-salad-with.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/09/mediterranean-warm-farro-salad-with.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 09:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carrot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Herbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Onion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oregano]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portobello Mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Side Dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tomato]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Warm Salad]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/09/17/mediterranean-warm-farro-salad-wi/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Autumn &#8220;When the leaves change hueThe air becomes nice and coolFall is upon us&#8221; My husband bought me a bag of organic farro in Costco store and I cook it a lot. This grain has a nice earthy flavor and can serve as a side dish or vegetarian meal. I have another variation for this farro dish on my blog &#8211; Farro with Mushrooms, Carrots &#38; Perfectly Poached Egg.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/09/mediterranean-warm-farro-salad-with.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mushroom Risotto with Coconut Milk</title>
		<link>/2014/04/mushroom-risotto-with-coconut-milk.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/04/mushroom-risotto-with-coconut-milk.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 23:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coconut milk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Risotto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Turmeric]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/04/25/mushroom-risotto-with-coconut-milk/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I started my risotto only with garlic, mushrooms and rice. The rest of the ingredients I was choosing during the process.  The coconut milk proved to be an excellent idea for the taste and touch of turmeric has given risotto a nice bright color. The end result &#8211; exquisitely tasty dish!]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/04/mushroom-risotto-with-coconut-milk.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stuffed Peppers with Spicy Rice &#038; Cabbage (Vegetarian)</title>
		<link>/2014/04/stuffed-peppers-with-spicy-rice-cabbage.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/04/stuffed-peppers-with-spicy-rice-cabbage.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 07:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baked]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabbage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carrot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peppers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Progresso]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spicy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stuffed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tomato sauce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/04/08/stuffed-peppers-with-spicy-rice-cabbage/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Recently I have received a package of PROGRESSO sauces to use in my recipes. Today I was making vegetarian dinner for my husband and did not feel like spending much time in the kitchen. Luckily, I have roasted tomato sauce for my recipe in advance, and hence &#8211; cooked the dish in no time. There is always something special about stuffed dishes, it&#8217;s like having the main ingredient with surprise flavors. Try not to over-bake the peppers, they are very nice when they still have a little crunch. The stuffing can be anything you&#8217;d like. First, I was thinking to use quinoa with mushrooms, but ended up using spicy rice with cabbage with outstanding results! PROGRESSO has another sauce I would like to try &#8211; creamy portobello mushroom, but that is for next time, probably with homemade ravioli or pasta. 🙂 Compensation was provided by General Mills via Federated Media.  The opinions expressed herein are those of the author and are not indicative of the opinions or positions of General Mills. For more easy dinner ideas, visit&#160;http://progresso.com/Products/Recipe-Starters]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/04/stuffed-peppers-with-spicy-rice-cabbage.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roasted Rosemary Pumpkin with Black Rice &#038; Cashew Nuts</title>
		<link>/2014/03/roasted-rosemary-pumpkin-with-black.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/03/roasted-rosemary-pumpkin-with-black.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 08:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Black rice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cashew Nuts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Herbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roasting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rosemary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/03/31/roasted-rosemary-pumpkin-with-black/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hearty and heart-healthy, this roasted butternut squash dish makes a warming main course for a weekday family dinner. Beautiful and simple plate for a Monday night.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/03/roasted-rosemary-pumpkin-with-black.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stuffed Tomatoes with Black Rice &#038; Basil</title>
		<link>/2014/03/stuffed-tomatoes-with-black-rice-basil.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/03/stuffed-tomatoes-with-black-rice-basil.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 06:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Basil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Black rice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carrot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Herbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[No-eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Onion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stuffed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tomato]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/03/12/stuffed-tomatoes-with-black-rice-basi/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In ancient China, Black Rice was known as &#8220;Emperor&#8217;s Rice&#8221;, and it was reserved exclusively for Chinese Royalty. Loaded with antioxidants, vitamin E and fiber, Black Rice is as versatile as it is delicious. Its slightly sweet, slightly nutty taste, combined with its distinctive dark color, makes it appealing to the eyes and the taste buds. One serving has the same amount of antioxidants as a single serving of cultivated blueberries &#8211; without all the sugar. Simple, healthy, delicious &#8211; and easy to prepare. Basil: Remarkable for its fresh, pungent flavor unlike that of another herb, basil is widely used in Mediterranean salads, especially Italian recipes. Basil leaves are tender and delicate and should be gently torn or snipped with scissors, rather than chopped with a knife.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/03/stuffed-tomatoes-with-black-rice-basil.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Potato Gnocchi with Baby Lima Beans</title>
		<link>/2014/03/potato-gnocchi-with-baby-lima-beans.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/03/potato-gnocchi-with-baby-lima-beans.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 19:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Butter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gnocchi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lemon Zest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lima beans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parmesan cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parsley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[potato]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/03/06/potato-gnocchi-with-baby-lima-beans/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are few things tastier than light, freshly cooked, fluffy potato gnocchi. The addition of certain spices in combination with other ingredients can elevate this simple foodstuff to heights of gourmet artistry. Around the house. I wish spring can come soon&#8230; Serves: 4 Ingredients: 1 lb. potato 1 egg 1 Tbsp. parsley, chopped 1 tsp salt freshly ground pepper 1 cup flour + more if need it 1/2 cup ricotta cheese 1 cup baby lima beans, (I used frozen kind) 1 tsp. lemon zest 2 Tbsp. butter 2 Tbsp. olive oil Parmesan cheese to serve Ingredients: Steam the potatoes in their skin, or boil them in salted water until tender but mot mushy, about 20-25 minutes. Don&#8217;t peel the potatoes before boiling, as they will absorb too much water. Drain well and cool them just long enough to be able to peel them. Put clean potatoes through a potato ricer or food mill. In a large bowl combine the potatoes with an egg, parsley, salt, pepper and ricotta cheese. Add the flour and using your fingertips mix them together until a fairly firm mass that doesn&#8217;t stick to your fingers. On a clean work surface, divide the dough into 4 [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/03/potato-gnocchi-with-baby-lima-beans.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
