<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Zakusky &#8211; Cooking Melangery</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/russian-monday/zakusky/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>from sauté to soufflé</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 20:44:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cropped-Untitled-1-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Zakusky &#8211; Cooking Melangery</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Cheese &#038; Garlic Salad</title>
		<link>/2016/03/russian-monday-cheese-garlic-salad.html</link>
					<comments>/2016/03/russian-monday-cheese-garlic-salad.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spring]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2016/03/26/russian-monday-cheese-garlic-salad/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Although, today is not a Monday but I feel this post is very appropriate for Easter. It was my husband’s idea to make a post about this salad. He loves it and remembers eating it back home on every holiday. The dish is very simple, but I am sure you will love the taste. Pick your favorite cheese or combination of cheeses. Amount of garlic is totally up to you, our family loves a lot of it-)) Also you can serve it on top of cherry or plum tomatoes, and fresh spring herbs would be a wonderful addition. Russian Orthodox Easter Day will be on May 1 this year. But I would love to wish Happy Easter to everyone who celebrates it this Sunday! Awake, thou wintry earth &#8211; Fling off thy sadness! Fair vernal flowers, laugh forth Your ancient gladness! ~Thomas Blackburn, &#8220;An Easter Hymn&#8221;]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2016/03/russian-monday-cheese-garlic-salad.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 8 Russian Appetizers for New Year&#8217;s Eve Celebration</title>
		<link>/2015/12/russian-monday-top-8-russian-appetizers.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/12/russian-monday-top-8-russian-appetizers.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 05:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Year's Eve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Still Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakuska]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/12/28/russian-monday-top-8-russian-appetizers/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Year in Russia is considered to be a family holiday, but many choose to have their New Year’s party in clubs or restaurants, or while being away on exotic beach vacations, or in the country setting with the company of friends. However, most often, it is still celebrated at home at the festive table. The richness of Russian holiday table has always been impressive for the imagination of the foreigner. Variety of smoked fish and caviar, jellied meats and cold cuts, salads, homemade pickled vegetables, and mushrooms – appetizers are practically countless. Unfortunately, with time, certain common appetizers such as sturgeon caviar became delicacies and often are out of reach for many. However, this has not affected the richness of the festive table – smoked meats, sausages, hams, and pates have taken their place on the menu. Traditional New Year’s salads are “Olivie”, “Mimoza” and “Herring under fur coat”. A wide variety of salads is a must –  with meat, with mushrooms, with fresh veggies. Salads are usually served in large bowls rather than as individual portions. Pickled vegetables and mushrooms are all-time favorites. It can be pickled cabbage, dilled and pickled cucumbers, and tomatoes, smoked and salted fish, [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/12/russian-monday-top-8-russian-appetizers.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: “Volovan s Gribamy” &#8211; Vol-au-vents with Creamy Mushroom &#038; Shrimp Filling</title>
		<link>/2015/11/russian-monday-volovan-s-gribamy-vol-au.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/11/russian-monday-volovan-s-gribamy-vol-au.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 19:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fish & Seafood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caviar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shrimp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stuffing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vol-au-vents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakuska]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/11/16/russian-monday-volovan-s-gribamy-vol-au/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vol-au-vent is a puffy tartlet from flaky dough. Dough raises up during baking and takes shape of a small cup or basket. Variety of fillings go into baked dough baskets  and they are served cold or hot. Vol-au-vents are of French origin, first time made by French chef Marie-Antoine Carême. Name of this pastry points to the type of dough used in it. The initial idea behind volauvents was to make them very lite as opposed to the ones made of shortcrust dough. There is another name for vol-au-vents – bouchées. Authorship of first bouchées is attributed to wife of King Louis XV, Maria Leschinsky. She loved small single bite type of foods and hence the name – “bouchées à la reine”, queen’s bites. Despite of vol-au-vents French origin, they are very popular in Russian cuisine, you can find variety of their recipes in old cook books of Soviet time. For more Russian recipes, visit Russian Cuisine page. My new still life &#8211; Zakusky: Traditional Russian Small Plates Vol-au-vents are popular worldwide as well. They are usually made a “single bite size”, but occasionally you can find large ones too stuffed with meat or fish. These usually are the main course and [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/11/russian-monday-volovan-s-gribamy-vol-au.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: Family Dinner &#8211; Cornish Hens Under a Brick, Roasted Potato &#038; Cucumber Salad</title>
		<link>/2015/03/russian-monday-family-dinner-cornish.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/03/russian-monday-family-dinner-cornish.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 23:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Main Dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poultry, Game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicken]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cornish hens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cucumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family dinner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parsley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roasted potato]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Winter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yogurt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/03/09/russian-monday-family-dinner-cornis/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[March can be a very tricky month. One day the sun is shining and birds are singing, but the next day you wake up and find a pile of snow from the overnight snowstorm on your doorstep. That is what happened to us a couple of days ago. The school was canceled, train service was suspended and life came to a complete standstill. My family was very happy; the fireplace was burning and I have treated my husband and kids with Russian traditional meal. The cooking took me 40 minutes most, simple and rustic, but very unique and delicious. Our day off was perfect &#8211; good food, the beautiful snowy view from our dining room and cozy atmosphere. We would like to see the first spring flowers but have yet enjoyed one of the last tricks winter has played on us. Welcome to our home!]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/03/russian-monday-family-dinner-cornish.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: &#8220;Shaneshky&#8221; &#8211; Baked Potato Buns with Sour Cream &#038; Cheese</title>
		<link>/2015/01/russian-monday-shaneshky-baked-potato.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/01/russian-monday-shaneshky-baked-potato.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 09:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Butter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Potatoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shaneshky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sour Cream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakuska]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/01/12/russian-monday-shaneshky-baked-potato/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[These tasty pastries are especially dear to me because they carry the taste of my childhood. When I was a schoolgirl during summer holidays my parents used to send me to spend some time with grandma in the countryside. My grandma used to live in the village, in house made of real logs with giant brick-made oven. She had large garden, veggie patch, chickens, sheep and even cows. These were unforgettable days of my childhood. My grandma used to get up at dawn, milk the cow, start the fire in the oven and put the dough to rise. By the time I was up hot potatoes-stuffed shaneshky were waiting for me on table, covered by a napkin next to a jug of warm fresh milk. I am happy to share this wonderful recipe so you too can experience the taste of my childhood. For more Russian recipes, visit Russian Cuisine page. Tormosov Viktor Mixaylovich]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/01/russian-monday-shaneshky-baked-potato.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: Salad &#8220;Olivier&#8221; &#8211; Potato Salad</title>
		<link>/2014/12/russian-monday-salad-olivier-potato.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/12/russian-monday-salad-olivier-potato.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 11:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carrots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicken]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Year's Eve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Olivier]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pickles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[potato]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scallions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakuska]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/12/29/russian-monday-salad-olivier-potato/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Even though in every Russian family Olivier salad is made in their own way with some secret ingredient, like grandma used to do it, let’s try to remember  where this dish came from and give thanks to the Russian chief of French origin named Lucien Olivier who invented the salad any New Years table seems empty without. Famous salad Olivier has been coined by the chef Lucien Olivier in 1860s. Lucien has been not only a cook, but he also owned “Hermitage” restaurant at Trubnaya Square in Moscow. His restaurant could easily compete with any Parisian establishment. His crown dish was the famous salad nicknamed after him which recipe he kept in complete secrecy. After chefs passing story of his dish got surrounded by rumors and the recipe was considered lost. There were many attempts to find Olivier’s records, but nobody was able to do it. In 1904 few chefs have recovered the recipe based on their knowledge of main ingredients. The following ingredients were on the list: pressed caviar (0.25 lbs), two grouses, veal tongue, boiled crayfish – 25 pc, soy – 0.5 can, 2 cucumbers, green salad leaves – 0.5 lbs, assorted pickled vegetables – 0.5 can, capers [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/12/russian-monday-salad-olivier-potato.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: Chicken Liver Pâté With Red Wine &#038; Cranberry Jelly</title>
		<link>/2014/12/russian-monday-chicken-liver-pate-with.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/12/russian-monday-chicken-liver-pate-with.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Butter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carrots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicken Liver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cranberries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jelly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Year's Eve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Onion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Red Wine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/12/15/russian-monday-chicken-liver-pate-wi/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[History of&#160;pâté&#160;is rooted in the distant past and many countries contest the right to be named its birthplace, however, by default, this right is held by France. In truth, French chefs have simply revived the dish loved by ancient Romans. Interestingly enough, in medieval times, pates were served as feast culmination and hence were decorated in the most luxurious fashion, often made with “surprise” inside, when live birds could fly out from inside of the dish brought into the feast hall. Often&#160;pâtés were cooked wrapped in the layer of dough, like pies. The dough was simply a wrapper and secondary to the stuffing, hence the word “pâté” has started being used only for what was inside of such pies. In Russia&#160;pâté is very popular and served on any festive table. I would like to present my own recipe unique in its use of wine jelly. This Chicken Liver Pâté With Red Wine &#38; Cranberry Jelly is great for your holiday table to be served with hot toasts. Bon appetite! For more Russian recipes, visit Russian Cuisine page.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/12/russian-monday-chicken-liver-pate-with.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: &#8220;Manti&#8221; &#8211; Steamed Buns Stuffed with Lamb</title>
		<link>/2014/10/russian-monday-manti-steamed-buns.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/10/russian-monday-manti-steamed-buns.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 07:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cumin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dinner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lamb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mane Dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sauce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sour Cream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steamed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stuffed]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/10/20/russian-monday-manti-steamed-buns/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Manti&#8221; (steamed buns with lamb filling) is a traditional meat dish of the people of Central Asia, Turkey, Mongolia, Korea, as well as of the Tartars and Bashkir of Russia. It is believed that manti originates from the outer regions of China, where Uyghur people of Xinjiang region have a dish named “mantou” which literally means “steamed bread”. Gradually, the recipe of the dish has spread from Xinjiang through Central Asia and beyond. But even today, Uyghur cooks are considered to be the best manti specialists in the world. This dish is popular in Russia and is usually served in many oriental restaurants. It is also easy to cook at home. Manti looks like regular dumplings, however, they are larger in size and cooked in a certain way. Meat for the filling has to be cut by hand and can never be ground since minced or ground meat loses all of its juice. Meat juice mixed with onions is the main taste component of manti, making it taste unlike any other dumplings. This particular recipe is for the Uzbek manti which are typically stuffed with lamb, however, mixes of meats are also used. Vegetables can be added into the filling too [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/10/russian-monday-manti-steamed-buns.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: Carrot Salad with Walnuts &#038; Garlic</title>
		<link>/2013/11/russian-monday-carrot-salad-with.html</link>
					<comments>/2013/11/russian-monday-carrot-salad-with.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carrots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mayonnaise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parsley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Side Dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walnuts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yogurt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakuska]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2013/11/25/russian-monday-carrot-salad-wi/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I would like to present you a simple salad recipe from my own childhood times. There has not ever been a complete holiday table in our house without this salad. I recall myself a little girl helping my mom to peel garlic and chop walnuts, and later, it has become my own dish I cooked preparing for the arrival of guests. Today, many years since, this salad is very popular with my family. It is quick to be cooked and it does not stay long. Another point of note – garlic is a valuable ingredient, which is especially important during winter months. Carrots and walnuts make this salad an excellent side for meat dishes adding special piquancy to the taste of meat. It is perfect for someone who does not like to spend much time in the kitchen and wants to make quick, tasty and simple vitamin-rich carrot salad. Try this recipe and I can assure you – you’ll love it! For more Russian recipes, visit Russian Cuisine page.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/11/russian-monday-carrot-salad-with.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: Buttery Potatoes with Garlic &#038; Fresh Herbs</title>
		<link>/2013/11/russian-monday-buttery-potatoes-with.html</link>
					<comments>/2013/11/russian-monday-buttery-potatoes-with.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 10:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Butter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parsley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[potato]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Side Dish]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2013/11/11/russian-monday-buttery-potatoes-wi/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Potato is a relative newcomer in Russian cuisine. It has started to occupy a regular spot on the dining table from the early 19th century, while prior to that turnips have been used in the same capacity, served boiled, mashed with butter or sour cream, fried, baked and used as a side to various dishes. Start of potato growing in Russia is usually attributed to Peter the Great. Unconfirmed historical myth mentions Peter the Great tasting potatoes for the first time while in Holland during one of this European travels. Impressed by the value of the new food item, he sends a sack of potatoes back to St. Petersburg, addressed to Count Sheremetev. However, proof of such royal parcel existence is lacking, but nevertheless, even if it was true, this would have been only one of the potato pathways into Russia. Initially, potatoes were considered outlandish exotic vegetable. Sprinkled with sugar they were served as a rare dainty dish at royal court balls and nobility banquets. Starting from 1764-1776 first potato patches have been cultivated in St. Petersburg, Novgorod, Riga and few other places. Gradually, Russian people have learned more about the benefits and usages of potato. 200 years old [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/11/russian-monday-buttery-potatoes-with.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: Mushrooms with Sour Cream Sauce &#8211; &#8220;Gribi v Smetane&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2013/11/russian-monday-mushrooms-with-sour.html</link>
					<comments>/2013/11/russian-monday-mushrooms-with-sour.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Butter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dinner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Onion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sour Cream]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2013/11/04/russian-monday-mushrooms-with-sour/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mushrooms are a traditional ingredient of Russian cuisine. For centuries, our ancestors used a bounty of forest to diversify their menu. And even today with an enormous variety of options, ingredients, recipes from around the world available to us true gourmets love tasty and fragrant mushrooms in sour cream. Boletus (“white mushroom”), chanterelle, armillaria, and champignon are four mushroom species cooked the most often. Sour cream is added to the sauce served with mushrooms or directly applied during frying or cooking process. Mushrooms with sour cream are traditional dish occupying an honorary place in all Russian cookbooks and it that can easily boast many centuries of history. For more Russian recipes, visit Russian Cuisine page. Forest berries and wild mushrooms are a wonderful gift of nature. They carry the fragrance of a pure forest and help maintain your good health and longevity.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/11/russian-monday-mushrooms-with-sour.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: &#8220;Shuba&#8221; &#8211; Beet Salad with Herring or &#8220;Herring under a fur coat&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2013/10/russian-monday-shuba-beet-salad-with.html</link>
					<comments>/2013/10/russian-monday-shuba-beet-salad-with.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 23:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fish & Seafood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carrots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dukan Diet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Herring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salmon row]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shuba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yogurt]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2013/10/14/russian-monday-shuba-beet-salad-wi/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Authorship of this wonderful salad is attributed to Anastas Bogomilov &#8211; merchant, the owner of a network of popular canteens and restaurants in Moscow at the beginning of 20th century. During late 1910’s Russia has been going through a lot of political and social turmoil eventually manifested in two revolutions of 1917. It has been very common for patrons of his restaurants adhering to opposing political views to get drunk and get into argument about the fate of the country. Arguments eventually were growing into a fight accompanied by broken plates, glasses and even furniture. Clever businessman and patriot, Anastas came up with the idea of good hearty snack which could represent a notion of national unification. “Herring under a fur coat” has been served for the first time on New Year&#8217;s Eve of 1919. The main ingredient of this dish was herring – a favorite treat of the working poor, or “proletarians”. With the addition of onions, potatoes, and carrots, covered by a layer of grated beets symbolizing red banner of the revolutionaries the salad was a sure hit. In order not to forget the enemies of the Soviets, the salad has been generously seasoned with Western invention – [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/10/russian-monday-shuba-beet-salad-with.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: Roasted Marrow Bones on Toast with Onion-Capers Salad</title>
		<link>/2013/10/russian-monday-roasted-marrow-bones-on.html</link>
					<comments>/2013/10/russian-monday-roasted-marrow-bones-on.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 09:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beef, Lamb, Veal, Pork]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Capers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Onion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parsley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pickles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roasted Marrow Bones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sunflower Oil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakuska]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2013/10/07/russian-monday-roasted-marrow-bones-on/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every ethnic Russian has an opinion about this drink, but let’s not rush with naming vodka a “national drink”, since it has been introduced in Russia by foreigners. The only justification for the term “national” is the level of this drink consumption. Usually, opinions about vodka differ drastically – some people like it and some can’t stand it. There is a view out there that vodka is a rough drink not suitable for ladies and it has to be drunk in one gulp after getting it freezing cold. Unfortunately, this view is quite wide-spread, but it is nevertheless completely wrong. The culture of vodka consumption has been practically ruined by the series of historical events in Russia over the course of the last hundred years.  The barbarian habit to snack drink after vodka instead of having an actual snack speaks volumes. General impoverishment as well as cultural degradation have played and are still playing the major role in the destruction of traditions when gastronomy has been simply held hostage by the unfortunate historical changes that are still unfolding to date. Let’s discuss how vodka and snacks for it must be properly served at the dinner table. Due to fall season [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/10/russian-monday-roasted-marrow-bones-on.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: Salted Cucumbers</title>
		<link>/2013/08/russian-monday-salted-cucumbers.html</link>
					<comments>/2013/08/russian-monday-salted-cucumbers.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 09:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Black current leaves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cherry leaves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cucumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fennel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fresh horseradish leaves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pickled]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preserves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2013/08/05/russian-monday-salted-cucumbers/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Even though the word “pickles” most often is used to refer to pickled cucumbers, this is a collective term. It applies to pickled, leavened or marinated vegetables, mushrooms, fruits, greens and even berries – just any fruits of the earth. The initial purpose of pickling raw vegetables was the preservation of the food for a longer term. Different nations had their own ways of picking and leavening depending on the climate they lived in. People in regions with a warmer climate, such as Southern and South-Eastern Europe, Transcaucasia, Central Asia traditionally dried and marinated their foods using vinegar (made from soured wine), since during warm winters it was easiest and the surest way to preserve food. Vinegar was also very accessible and cheap. In colder regions of northern Europe and counties like Russia and Ukraine methods of preserving food for longer terms got developed very differently – salting, pickling, and leavening do not utilize any kinds of vinegar. It is a historical fact that in the 12th century Russia marinated cucumbers and leavened cabbage were very common. The greens (dill, tarragon, basil, savory, coriander, celery, parsley, horseradish) used for cucumbers picking must have a specific taste so it would become [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/08/russian-monday-salted-cucumbers.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: &#8220;Pirozhki&#8221; &#8211; Baked Stuffed Pies</title>
		<link>/2013/07/russian-monday-pirozhki-baked-stuffed.html</link>
					<comments>/2013/07/russian-monday-pirozhki-baked-stuffed.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dough]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pirozhki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stuffed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yeast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2013/07/29/russian-monday-pirozhki-baked-stuffed/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Homemade Pirozhki are supposed to be hot and rosy. Word “pirozhki” means “small pies”. These are small crescent or oval-shaped baked goods usually made from yeast-based dough. Pirozhki remember the whole history of the culinary development of Slavic nations and they are part of many Russian traditions. For generations, pirozhki recipes have been passed from mother to daughter as methods of preparing the dough were getting more sophisticated and variety of stuffing has been growing. Today there is an enormous number of various pirozhki recipes. The dough can be yeast or water-based, with or without butter, puff pastry or plain etc. Pastry dough is the one allowing your fantasy to run wild. While using pastry dough your pirozhki can be stuffed with potatoes, cabbage, meats or mushrooms, apples, veggies, eggs, and greens. Pastry dough works well with practically any stuffing. Puff pastry dough works equally well. Pirozhki are a great snack. They also can be a nice breakfast or reminder about your grandmother or your cherished childhood memory. Cooking pirozhki is easy and pleasant – pick the stuffing, add some love and warmth of your soul, and have them ready!]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/07/russian-monday-pirozhki-baked-stuffed.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: Vinegrette &#8211; Vegetable Salad</title>
		<link>/2013/06/russian-monday-vinegrette-vegetable.html</link>
					<comments>/2013/06/russian-monday-vinegrette-vegetable.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 09:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carrots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Herring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Onion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Potatoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Root Vegetable Salad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sunflower Oil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vinegar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vinegrette]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2013/06/10/russian-monday-vinegrette-vegetable/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vinegrette (pronounced as “vee-ne-gret”, from French “vinaigrette”) is widely popular in Europe as well as in tsars time Russia salad dressing made of vinegar, olive oil, and mustard. The name originates from a diminutive form of word vinegar (or in French “vinaigre”). In modern-day Russian word “vinegrette” is used for a salad made of boiled beets, potatoes, carrots, pickles, scallions or onions as well as pickled cabbage. The salad is dressed with sunflower oil or mayo; even though in the past only mustard-based “vinaigrette” dressing was utilized and that has given the name to this dish. Vinegrette was brought into Russian cuisine in the 19th century, most likely either from Germany or Scandinavian countries. British cookbook of 1845 for example, includes a recipe of “Swedish herring salad” made of Norwegian herring, beets, potatoes, and pickles, apple mashed with egg yolk served with a dressing made of oil, vinegar, grated egg yolks, and sour cream. Classic Russian vinegrette is made of: beets, carrots, potatoes – boiled and cooled off, pickles and pickled cabbage, onions and/or scallions. All ingredients are taken in approximately equal proportion, even though a bit lesser (than any other used veggie) amount of onions and a bit larger amount [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/06/russian-monday-vinegrette-vegetable.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
