<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Miscellaneous &#8211; Cooking Melangery</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/miscellaneous/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>from sauté to soufflé</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 01:30:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cropped-Untitled-1-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Miscellaneous &#8211; Cooking Melangery</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How A Balanced Diet Can Prevent Obesity</title>
		<link>/2023/06/how-a-balanced-diet-can-prevent-obesity.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 01:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[article]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=7404</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Even the latest med technology can&#8217;t completely cure one of the nation&#8217;s most urgent health problems: obesity. More than 42% of American adults are obese, with rates steadily growing. That&#8217;s over 4 out of 10 people—significantly higher than a decade ago, when no state had an adult obesity rate over 35%. Yet while this problem is multifactored and will take many interdisciplinary solutions to solve completely, there is one simple, vital step almost everyone can take to lower their risk: a balanced diet. But why exactly is this a vital strategy for you to adopt? Read on to learn more about what obesity is, how it impacts your health—and how a balanced diet can help mitigate the effects of this condition. Obesity and your health Obesity is the excess of fat. Though often confused with being overweight, the body mass index (BMI) classification system—which determines how your weight measures compared to your height—shows a significant difference between overweight vs obesity. You&#8217;re considered overweight or pre-obese if you have a BMI of 25 to 29.9, and obese if you reach a BMI of 30. Though both overweight and obese individuals risk developing heart disease, high blood pressure, and diabetes, obesity is more likely to [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Connection between a tasty pizza and overcoming depression.</title>
		<link>/2022/01/connection-between-a-tasty-pizza-and-overcoming-depression.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 23:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[article]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pizza]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=7353</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;re in the mood for a little lighthearted reading, we thought we&#8217;d share with you this humorous and informative piece on the connection between pizza and depression. It&#8217;s worth a read — we guarantee that even if you&#8217;re not feeling depressed, it&#8217;ll leave you feeling better than ever! Ok, now let&#8217;s get serious for a second:&#160;overcoming depression is extremely difficult. There are many things to consider, such as finding safe ways to express your emotions and thoughts, trying new activities, finding accountability partners who will positively influence your recovery process&#8230; But whatever your journey entails or wherever it may lead, don&#8217;t forget that people love and support you just as much as they always have. You&#8217;re not alone. What&#8217;s the connection between a tasty pizza and overcoming depression? Psychiatrist and psychoanalyst Irvin D. Yalom, MD, wrote Love&#8217;s Executioner: The Myth of the Self-Absorbed Adult. He presents his take on &#8220;rebellious children&#8221; about adults who have trouble connecting with others in this book. He says that some people, such as rebels and psychopaths, use food to cope with their anxieties and stressors. Therefore Dr. Yalom believes that when depressed people eat pizza, they show signs of self-soothing behavior. We couldn&#8217;t [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 Unexpected Cooking Ingredients You Should Have On Hand In Your Kitchen</title>
		<link>/2022/01/7-unexpected-cooking-ingredients-you-should-have-on-hand-in-your-kitchen.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 16:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cofee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sugar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=7379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cooking is an activity that you will get better at over time. Some cooks will struggle with portion size and cooking times when they first start out; however, others will take to the practice like a duck to water. This does not mean that you cannot continue to improve though. The ingredients you use in your recipes can really make a difference, and sometimes it pays to go off the beaten path. If you want your next meals to taste unique, consider having some of these unexpected ingredients to hand in your kitchen. Sugar Sugar is an obvious staple for most bakers, although, you will still find this ingredient useful when cooking up some savory dishes. When cooking something with vegetables, you will find that these ingredients contain their own natural sweetness. This helps to cut out some of the acidity in some meals, especially ones that are heavy on oil or vinegar. However, not every dish will require enough vegetables to do the job. Therefore, you may find it beneficial to add a pinch of sugar to your bolognese or curry sauces to give them a bit more flavor. Coffee On the topic of pasta dishes, there are two [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Launching A Mobile Cocktail Bar: Practical Tips For Entrepreneurial Mixologists </title>
		<link>/2022/01/launching-a-mobile-cocktail-bar-practical-tips-for-entrepreneurial-mixologists.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[article]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cocktail bar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[practical tips]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=7367</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For passionate cocktail lovers, launching your own bar is the ultimate dream. However, high start-up costs and an uncertain economy might make it hard for you to get started. Thankfully, there are ways to reduce the initial cost and future proof your business. One great solution is to consider launching a mobile cocktail bar.&#160; Mobile cocktail bars can be housed in the back of trucks or on trailers and can easily be launched at events such as weddings and music festivals or in open spaces to attract crowds of party-lovers. Whatever you intend to do with your mobile cocktail bar, you need to make sure that you do it right if you want to succeed.&#160; That’s why we’ve put together this list of practical tips to help you get your mobile cocktail bar off to an amazing start! Create A Plan Mobile cocktail bars come in all shapes and sizes, so the first step is to create a plan. Think about who you want to attract, where you plan to host events and what you want to offer. Some mobile cocktail bars serve food, while others have a limited menu of speciality cocktails based around one specific alcohol. Whatever you [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Balanced Diet: What Is It and How to Achieve It?</title>
		<link>/2021/06/balanced-diet-what-is-it-and-how-to-achieve-it.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 23:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[article]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cooking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=7371</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A balanced diet is a diet that includes specific amounts and proportions of different types of food so that requirements for calories, protein, minerals, vitamins, and replacement nutrients are adequate, and small amounts of additional nutrients are retained to support survival during brief periods of leanness. Additionally, a balanced diet should provide bioactive phytochemicals with positive health benefits, such as fiber, antioxidants, and nutraceuticals. A balanced diet should contain approximately 60-70% of total calories from carbohydrates, 10-12% from protein, and 20-25% from fat. You should check food recipes. Health benefits of a balanced diet If you want to eat healthy, you should know all of the benefits for your body and mind. If you choose a balanced diet, that helps you increase energy, improves your body work, strengthens your immune system and other great things. Other big advantages are meeting your nutritional needs. A varied, balanced diet provides the nutrients you need to prevent symptoms of deficiency. Prevent and treat certain diseases. Eating a healthy diet can reduce the risk of certain diseases, such as diabetes, cancer and heart disease. It also helps treat diabetes and high blood pressure. Following a special diet can relieve symptoms and help you better [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicken of the Woods Cream of Mushroom Soup</title>
		<link>/2019/10/chicken-of-the-woods-cream-of-mushroom-soup.html</link>
					<comments>/2019/10/chicken-of-the-woods-cream-of-mushroom-soup.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 01:27:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetable and Grain Soups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buckwheat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicken of the woods mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foraging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wild]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is a hearty soup that captures the flavor of the Chicken of the woods. It goes best with a full-bodied Zinfandel for a midday lunch! Laetiporus sulphureous known as Chicken-of-the-Woods The common name of this a fungus derives from the fact that, when cooked, this mushroom has the texture of fresh chicken breast. The fungus is one of a larger group of fungi known as polypores &#8211; similar to boletes in that the underside of the cap is composed of pores rather than gills. In most cases polyphonies are inedible because of their woody texture. Some, however, are quite good to eat, and the chicken of the woods is among the best known. It is also known as the sulfur mushroom because the underside of the cap is a bright yellow color. The top side is red-orange, which makes it very easy to identify. These fungi can be seen growing out of fallen and rotting trees from summer to late fall. Older specimens take a long time to cook because of their woody texture. Younger specimens take just a short time to make them soft and chewable. The part of the fungus farthest from the base is the most [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/10/chicken-of-the-woods-cream-of-mushroom-soup.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Will the Instant Pot be Your New Best Friend in the Kitchen?</title>
		<link>/2019/08/will-the-instant-pot-be-your-new-best-friend-in-the-kitchen.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 15:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=7221</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cooking is a fundamental part of life but is also something that people the world over enjoy doing. Some people train for years to become a chef, while others are more than happy whipping up something in their kitchen to feed the family. Whether or not you are a professional chef, there are a number of different pieces of equipment that are vital to the success of any kitchen. Cooking pots and pans come in all shapes and sizes, with some having been developed to cater for a specific type of cooking. For example, a slow cooker is a great way to slowly cook a Sunday roast, but you wouldn’t use it to boil a couple of eggs or to make a cake. The same goes for a pressure cooker. It’s a great way to cook meat so that it stays soft and tender, but it’s going to be much use for you if you are planning to cook some pasta. Having all of these different pots takes up a lot of space in your kitchen, and if your home isn’t so large, you could very easily find yourself being crowded out of your kitchen by the very pots and [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mediterranean Snacks for Seniors that Pack a Nutritious Punch</title>
		<link>/2017/04/mediterranean-snacks-for-seniors-that.html</link>
					<comments>/2017/04/mediterranean-snacks-for-seniors-that.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 15:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mediterranean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nutritious]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seniors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snack]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2017/04/18/mediterranean-snacks-for-seniors-tha/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Mediterranean diet is considered to be one of the world’s healthiest. Ingredients like olives, dates, whole grains and fresh vegetables are flavorful, nutritious, and satisfying. Seniors need a healthy snack in between meals to keep their blood sugar level stable. Here are a few snack ideas that are excellent choices for seniors and their health benefits. Kalamata Olives These olives are a perfect snack when on the go. The salty flavor of kalamata olives works well with the natural and healthy oils. Olives like these are high in antioxidants like oleic acid, tyrosol, and hydroxytyrosol. Antioxidants help repair damaged cells and can reverse aging. Try crumbling some feta cheese over the olives for a variation. Crackers and Tuna Ditch the mayonnaise for this snack. Try eating tuna fresh (or packaged) with cracked pepper, and a drizzle of olive oil and red wine vinegar then topped with diced scallions. Tuna is high in Omega 3 essential fatty acids. They protect the heart and brain. Seniors can enjoy their tuna salad with whole grain crackers. Dried Fruit and Nuts A handful of mixed nuts will level out blood sugar levels by providing a protein boost. They are also full of omega-3 [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2017/04/mediterranean-snacks-for-seniors-that.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy Spring Gardening  #OXOSpringGardening</title>
		<link>/2015/05/happy-spring-gardening.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/05/happy-spring-gardening.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 23:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#OXOSpringGardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berry bush]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fruit Tree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garden tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spring]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/05/06/happy-spring-gardening/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tucked behind a tangle of brush at the bottom of the gentle hill of our townhouse backyards is a cleared space of about a quarter of an acre. Several of our neighbors proudly refer to it as &#8220;the community garden&#8221;. A few years ago, Joe and some of our other more agriculturally inclined neighbors decided to rescue a plot of land from the bramble, vines and thorns that did little for us but shelter the herd of deer that ravaged our ornamental gardens. Now the square clearing is home to neat rows of asparagus, rhubarb, raspberries and blackberries, onions and shallots, garlic, winter squash and pumpkins for late summer and potatoes for the fall. Small handfuls of sugar-sweet asparagus have already graced our dinner table! &#160;There will be tall and lacy-looking sweet fennel and colorful bread poppies. There will also be an abundance of fragrant herbs, including dill, chamomile, lavender, mint and lemon balm. For exotic beauty, a passion flower vine is climbing determinedly up its trellis. There are currant bushes, with three colors of berries: pink, red and black. We have three types of apple and Asian pear trees, two types each of peach and cherry and two paw [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/05/happy-spring-gardening.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are You Ready for Spring? #OXOSpringCleaning</title>
		<link>/2015/03/are-you-ready-for-spring.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/03/are-you-ready-for-spring.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 23:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[‪#‎oxospringcleaning‬]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cleaning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kitchen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oxo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spring]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/03/25/are-you-ready-for-spring/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Spring is finally around the corner after the endless cold days and this means new start and new beginning. Everything slowly starts to wake up as sun warms up the ground. I love first sunny days, I open my windows to let fresh air to come into our bedrooms. Once you can see first flowers under the trees you know Easter is coming soon. Along with cooking special foods during such time, I like to give my house a spark and start my spring cleaning. I do laundry almost every day &#8211; all winter jackets, scarves and sweaters need a good wash. Winter boots are going into their boxes until next cold season. When all of this is in order, I start freshening up room by room. I buy many flowers and herbs in early spring, something unique for every room. Tulips usually go on my dining table, lilies of the valley – to bedrooms. Fresh mint on a countertop brings lovely aroma in a kitchen. Don&#8217;t you just love new beginning? Recently, I have got a box from Oxo, very timely it was filled with many cleaning tools. I would love to share with you some of my favorite [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/03/are-you-ready-for-spring.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Have a Magical Christmas &#038; a Happy New Year!</title>
		<link>/2014/12/have-magical-christmas-happy-new-year.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/12/have-magical-christmas-happy-new-year.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 16:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Organizing the party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Winter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/12/23/have-magical-christmas-happy-new-year/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Fair be the path beneath your feet. Bright be the skies above you- Where&#8217;er you go, still may you meet Friends that will truly love you&#8221;. How to organize a successful party. If you are planning to have a holiday party in your house you might like to know a few helpful tips for organizing without stress. First of all you will need a guest list, it is a list of people you would like to invite. After you make that list you should call everyone or use an old fashioned way by sending printed-out invitations by mail with information about the party such as: the date and time, the address, the theme of the party and the confirmation date. You need to be confirmed about how many quests can attend the party. After that is settled you need to start thinking about the menu. One question needs to be answered about the style of your party: is it going to be a sit down party with many different courses or a buffet style where quests can serve the food and drinks themselves. This is a very important part of creating the menu, because these two styles should have different [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/12/have-magical-christmas-happy-new-year.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>First November Snow</title>
		<link>/2014/11/first-november-snow.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/11/first-november-snow.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 15:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Autumn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[First Snow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[November]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reportage]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/11/17/first-november-snow/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is no recipe today, just beautiful pictures of first November snow and happy colors. Take a walk with me around my neighborhood. Enjoy!]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/11/first-november-snow.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My New Orderly Kitchen</title>
		<link>/2014/10/my-new-orderly-kitchen.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/10/my-new-orderly-kitchen.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 13:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Containers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Giveaway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kitchen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Organizing the kitchen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oxo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop OXO containers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Remodel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[storage]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/10/13/my-new-orderly-kitchen/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My dear readers, as many of you know that during the summer time, my blog was a little lonely as I did not post any new recipes for you. Unfortunately, I did not take a vacation to some exotic place and forgot all about the blog nor did I abandon it. We were renovating our kitchen and it took us four long month to do so. In the beginning, we only planned to change our cabinets, but we ended up changing pretty much everything: floor, lights, walls, fireplace, furniture and dishwasher. These are our &#8220;in process&#8221; photos. Sorry about the quality of the images, they were taken with my phone. Before After It was a very long process, and when I look back, I don&#8217;t know how we accomplished it. Of course, we had amazing help of the architect from the William Draper Cabinetmaker, without whom it would have been impossible. He is an &#8220;old school&#8221; brilliant guy, not to mention a pleasant person, who came to our house with architectural plans for our kitchen drawn in pencil by hand. So, you see how fortunate we are to have somebody like that in our remodeling. His attention to detail was [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/10/my-new-orderly-kitchen.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>After the Rain&#8230;</title>
		<link>/2014/05/after-rain.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/05/after-rain.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 22:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Summer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/05/30/after-rain/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Spring rain&#160; conveyed under the trees in drops&#8221;. Matsuo Basho&#8217;s Haiku]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/05/after-rain.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Have a Wonderful Thanksgiving!</title>
		<link>/2013/11/have-wonderful-thanksgiving.html</link>
					<comments>/2013/11/have-wonderful-thanksgiving.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postcard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thank you]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thanksgiving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2013/11/28/have-wonderful-thanksgiving/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thank you for letting me be a part of your life!]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/11/have-wonderful-thanksgiving.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lavender Cupcakes with Vanilla Lemon Marshmallow Topping</title>
		<link>/2013/07/lavender-cupcakes-with-vanilla-lemon.html</link>
					<comments>/2013/07/lavender-cupcakes-with-vanilla-lemon.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 15:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cupcake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lavender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lemon Zest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marshmallow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sugar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanilla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2013/07/08/lavender-cupcakes-with-vanilla-lemon/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lavender has a potent flavor, but that doesn&#8217;t mean it has to be overpowering in dessert. In these beautiful Lavender Cupcakes with Lemon Marshmallow Topping, the vibrancy of lemon both brings out and helps temper the musky floral qualities of lavender. The flavors harmonize beautifully and make for cupcakes much more interesting. Note: Since different varieties of lavender have different strengths, make sure to taste the syrup. When the lavender is subtle or strong enough to suit your taste, it&#8217;s time to strain it, even if it&#8217;s a few minutes more or less than time frame in this recipe.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/07/lavender-cupcakes-with-vanilla-lemon.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Food Blog Forum Orlando (FL) 2013</title>
		<link>/2013/05/food-blog-forum-orlando-fl-2013.html</link>
					<comments>/2013/05/food-blog-forum-orlando-fl-2013.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 01:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Event]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food Blog Forum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grand Floridian Resort]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kitchen Aid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orlando]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oxo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2013/05/23/food-blog-forum-orlando-fl-2013/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My dear readers, Some of you probably did not know that last weekend I have traveled to Orlando, Florida. I apologize for not posting any recipes last week. I had the honor to be selected to take part in Food Bloggers Forum among the hundred participants from around the country. These have been magical three days for me and my family. Besides, stay at the gorgeous Grand Floridian resort we also had tickets to four Disney parks, and while I have been making new friends and learning about blogging my family had an exciting time visiting &#8220;Tower of Terror&#8221; and riding Mount Everest roller coaster. The time spent was priceless and my kids wanted to stay longer. I would love to share a few moments from our trip. I hope you enjoy my reporting! Food Blog Forum 2013, took place at Disney’s Grand Floridian Resort. Amazing! We had outstanding speakers &#8211; Scott &#38; Jaden from Steamy Kitchen, Todd &#38; Diane from WhiteOnRiceCouple, Lindsay from Love &#38; Olive Oil&#160;and Julie. Thank you for all you&#8217;ve done for this unforgettable event. We left the conference with gifts from Oxo, Kitchen Aid, Florida Dairy Farmers, and many more. Our lunch was provided by [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/05/food-blog-forum-orlando-fl-2013.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
