<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Russian Monday &#8211; Cooking Melangery</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/russian-monday/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>from sauté to soufflé</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 22:34:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cropped-Untitled-1-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Russian Monday &#8211; Cooking Melangery</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: Buckwheat Soup with Cauliflower &#038; Turmeric &#8211; Florida Trip (Part One)</title>
		<link>/2018/09/russian-monday-buckwheat-soup-with-cauliflower-turmeric-florida-trip-part-one.html</link>
					<comments>/2018/09/russian-monday-buckwheat-soup-with-cauliflower-turmeric-florida-trip-part-one.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 03:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetable and Grain Soups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buckwheat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cauliflower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Herbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muchrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Turmeric]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=3614</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the weather turns colder and fall steps in, &#8220;cold weather soups&#8221; are an indispensable part of the menu. I would like to share with you one of my favorites &#8211; buckwheat soup!&#160;It is filling, super healthy and delicious. When it is raining or freezing outside, what else is better than to snuggle on the couch in your PJs, with a warm blanket, good book or film and a huge bowl of warm yummy soup? For me personally, soups are good in any weather &#8211; &#160;lentil soup, chicken soup, potato carrot, and definitely buckwheat soup are on my &#8220;short list&#8221;. But first &#8211; a little story. Today is a very special Russian Monday. One week ago, I was visiting my dear friends in Winter Park, Florida. They are also huge fans of my blog and my fine art photography. And it happened to be that Russian Monday is their favorite chapter on my blog. One thing leads to another and we found ourselves cooking Russian food for sixteen people for Monday evening. The menu was simple but creative. Our starters were roasted marrow bones with pickled onions, small sandwiches with&#160;fish, caviar, and vegetables, potato salad &#8220;Olivier&#8221;, and amazing cheese tray [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/09/russian-monday-buckwheat-soup-with-cauliflower-turmeric-florida-trip-part-one.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cheese &#038; Garlic Salad</title>
		<link>/2016/03/russian-monday-cheese-garlic-salad.html</link>
					<comments>/2016/03/russian-monday-cheese-garlic-salad.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spring]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2016/03/26/russian-monday-cheese-garlic-salad/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Although, today is not a Monday but I feel this post is very appropriate for Easter. It was my husband’s idea to make a post about this salad. He loves it and remembers eating it back home on every holiday. The dish is very simple, but I am sure you will love the taste. Pick your favorite cheese or combination of cheeses. Amount of garlic is totally up to you, our family loves a lot of it-)) Also you can serve it on top of cherry or plum tomatoes, and fresh spring herbs would be a wonderful addition. Russian Orthodox Easter Day will be on May 1 this year. But I would love to wish Happy Easter to everyone who celebrates it this Sunday! Awake, thou wintry earth &#8211; Fling off thy sadness! Fair vernal flowers, laugh forth Your ancient gladness! ~Thomas Blackburn, &#8220;An Easter Hymn&#8221;]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2016/03/russian-monday-cheese-garlic-salad.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blini &#8211; Vanilla Crepes with Berries</title>
		<link>/2016/03/russian-monday-blini-vanilla-crepes.html</link>
					<comments>/2016/03/russian-monday-blini-vanilla-crepes.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crepes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fruit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magazine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maslenitsa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[publications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Still Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanilla extract]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2016/03/07/russian-monday-blini-vanilla-crepes/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“Maslenitsa” is a Russian carnival week originating from pre-Christian times. It was celebrated around spring solstice and was dedicated to the boy-Sun named Xors becoming a man-Sun named Yarilo. The main dish of the holiday week are pancakes (or “blini” in Russian) in all their varieties. Their round shape symbolizes the Sun. Later on, after Christianity came to Russia, the holidays fell on the Great Lent, hence the decision was made to move the celebration right before the fasting. During Maslenitsa, older people were using a chance to share their wisdom with the youth by puzzling them with this riddle: “Maslenitsa is forty Grandmothers granddaughter, thirty Brothers sister, three mothers and one father&#8217;s daughter.” The answer to this riddle was an explanation of the sacred knowledge of the structure of the universe the elders believed in. For more information about &#8220;Maslenitsa&#8221; you can read here and here. My new still life &#8220;Long Winter&#8221;- prints are available for sale. Swedish magazine &#8220;La Prestige&#8221; has published my interview in their February issue. They have included 6 pages of Russian cuisine recipes from my &#8220;Russian Monday&#8221; collection featuring my photography. I am very happy to bring this information to my readers in Europe and everywhere else in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2016/03/russian-monday-blini-vanilla-crepes.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kurnik &#8211; Chicken Pie with Mushrooms, Kasha, Eggs &#038; Homemade Chicken Broth</title>
		<link>/2016/02/russian-monday-kurnik-chicken-pie-with.html</link>
					<comments>/2016/02/russian-monday-kurnik-chicken-pie-with.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 23:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Main Dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poultry, Game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Celery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicken broth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crepes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dinner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fennel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kurnik]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Main dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Onion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Turnips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2016/02/22/russian-monday-kurnik-chicken-pie-wi/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is not your everyday meal, but rather a very special occasion one. If you have invited dearest friends for dinner or perhaps you’d like to spoil your family with a great dish, this is what you need to cook! It is complicated and time consuming, but it is worth every minute of your time. It has taken me total of two days, including preparation of broth and two fillings on a first day, and then putting a pie together and baking on a second day. You can probably be done in one day, if you don’t need to photograph every step of the recipe-)) It may take about 3- 4 hours, including homemade broth and everything else. Of course you are not going to cook this every day, but it is such a grand dish, very delicious and aesthetically beautiful. I hope you enjoy my post today, I put a lot of effort to bring this to you. Bon appetite! For more Russian recipes, visit Russian Cuisine page. Chicken pie (“kurnick” in Russian) is the most famous of Russian pies, the king of pies, peak of national culinary arts. It is known from historical documents of the time, chicken [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2016/02/russian-monday-kurnik-chicken-pie-with.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yellow Split Pea Soup with Smoked Ham Shank &#8211; &#8220;Gorochovy Soup&#8221;</title>
		<link>/2016/01/russian-monday-yellow-split-pea-soup.html</link>
					<comments>/2016/01/russian-monday-yellow-split-pea-soup.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Meat and Poultry Soups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homemade croutons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Onion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parsley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Potatoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smoked meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Split peas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Winter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2016/01/25/russian-monday-yellow-split-pea-soup/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I recall this soup from my childhood, my school and even kindergarten years. Pea soup is very rich, fragrant and delicious. It is also very good in cold weather. The cooking of it is quite simple and fast. 20-25 years ago you could get peas at any store in Russia in few varieties – yellow, green, whole or halves. The halves were especially popular for some reason, they were cheap and in demand. Pea soup in Germany is practically a national dish and usually is served with smoked pork. Similarly, in Netherlands pea soup is cooked from crushed green peas with pork. Russian version of this soup is cooked with potatoes and served with crackers or toast. This recipe is my grandma’s – she used to make pea soup with smoked ribs and served it with garlic croutons made in the oven. Fantastically delicious! For more Russian recipes, visit Russian Cuisine page.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2016/01/russian-monday-yellow-split-pea-soup.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 8 Russian Appetizers for New Year&#8217;s Eve Celebration</title>
		<link>/2015/12/russian-monday-top-8-russian-appetizers.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/12/russian-monday-top-8-russian-appetizers.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 05:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Year's Eve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Still Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakuska]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/12/28/russian-monday-top-8-russian-appetizers/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Year in Russia is considered to be a family holiday, but many choose to have their New Year’s party in clubs or restaurants, or while being away on exotic beach vacations, or in the country setting with the company of friends. However, most often, it is still celebrated at home at the festive table. The richness of Russian holiday table has always been impressive for the imagination of the foreigner. Variety of smoked fish and caviar, jellied meats and cold cuts, salads, homemade pickled vegetables, and mushrooms – appetizers are practically countless. Unfortunately, with time, certain common appetizers such as sturgeon caviar became delicacies and often are out of reach for many. However, this has not affected the richness of the festive table – smoked meats, sausages, hams, and pates have taken their place on the menu. Traditional New Year’s salads are “Olivie”, “Mimoza” and “Herring under fur coat”. A wide variety of salads is a must –  with meat, with mushrooms, with fresh veggies. Salads are usually served in large bowls rather than as individual portions. Pickled vegetables and mushrooms are all-time favorites. It can be pickled cabbage, dilled and pickled cucumbers, and tomatoes, smoked and salted fish, [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/12/russian-monday-top-8-russian-appetizers.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roasted Lemony Duck with Buttery Quince &#8211; “Utka &#038; Aiva”</title>
		<link>/2015/12/russian-monday-roasted-lemony-duck-with.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/12/russian-monday-roasted-lemony-duck-with.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 16:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Main Dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poultry, Game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Butter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dinner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Duck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Honey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lemon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quince]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roasted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/12/14/russian-monday-roasted-lemony-duck-wi/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many people, when they think of duck, think only of roast duck. In reality there are so many interesting ways to prepare duck that, with the real connoisseurs, roast duck often takes a a back seat. For instance, steamed or boiled duck may be attractively combined with vegetables in Chinese-style recipes. Or duck may be braised and served with any one of a number of delicious sauces. But, personally I always come back to roasting the duck, with different herbs, spices, fruits and grains. Here is a recipe I created for upcoming holidays &#8211; roasted duck, with ginger and sweet honey, stuffed with lemons. I served it with fried pan buttery quince and few fermented and pickled vegetables. If you looking to cook something different for Christmas I hope you will try my recipe for simple roasted duck. Back in Russia my mom often cooked roast duck for the holidays. I remember the aroma in our tiny kitchen when duck stuffed with apples has been served with buckwheat or sauerkraut after being roasted for a long time. I did not like it as much then as I love it today. But this also brings me a lot of joy to [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/12/russian-monday-roasted-lemony-duck-with.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: “Volovan s Gribamy” &#8211; Vol-au-vents with Creamy Mushroom &#038; Shrimp Filling</title>
		<link>/2015/11/russian-monday-volovan-s-gribamy-vol-au.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/11/russian-monday-volovan-s-gribamy-vol-au.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 19:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fish & Seafood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caviar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shrimp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stuffing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vol-au-vents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakuska]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/11/16/russian-monday-volovan-s-gribamy-vol-au/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vol-au-vent is a puffy tartlet from flaky dough. Dough raises up during baking and takes shape of a small cup or basket. Variety of fillings go into baked dough baskets  and they are served cold or hot. Vol-au-vents are of French origin, first time made by French chef Marie-Antoine Carême. Name of this pastry points to the type of dough used in it. The initial idea behind volauvents was to make them very lite as opposed to the ones made of shortcrust dough. There is another name for vol-au-vents – bouchées. Authorship of first bouchées is attributed to wife of King Louis XV, Maria Leschinsky. She loved small single bite type of foods and hence the name – “bouchées à la reine”, queen’s bites. Despite of vol-au-vents French origin, they are very popular in Russian cuisine, you can find variety of their recipes in old cook books of Soviet time. For more Russian recipes, visit Russian Cuisine page. My new still life &#8211; Zakusky: Traditional Russian Small Plates Vol-au-vents are popular worldwide as well. They are usually made a “single bite size”, but occasionally you can find large ones too stuffed with meat or fish. These usually are the main course and [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/11/russian-monday-volovan-s-gribamy-vol-au.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Lenivie Golubtsy&#8221; &#8211; Lazy Style Cabbage Rolls</title>
		<link>/2015/10/russian-monday-lenivie-golubtsy-lazy.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/10/russian-monday-lenivie-golubtsy-lazy.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 12:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beef, Lamb, Veal, Pork]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Main Dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabbage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Golubtsy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ground Beef]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lazy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Main dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stuffed Cabbage Rolls]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/10/26/russian-monday-lenivie-golubtsy-lazy/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nobody knows exact origin of golubtsy (pronounced in Russian as “go-loob-zy”), i.e. Russian traditional stuffed cabbage dish, neither origin of its name. One thing is for certain – this dish is tasty, satisfying and impossible to get bored with due to tens of variations of the same recipe. One of such variations is named “lazy golubtsy”. Usually it is a good option when you don’t have much time to wrap traditional forcemeat with rice into cabbage leaves, or simply don’t want to bother with that. In such case stuffing can be placed in layers between cabbage leaves, or simply mixed together with shredded cabbage. I would like to offer you the recipe passed to me by my mom. Full tablespoon of sour cream is a perfect condiment to serve with golubtsy. For more Russian recipes, visit Russian Cuisine page. Lazy Style Cabbage Rolls]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/10/russian-monday-lenivie-golubtsy-lazy.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: &#8220;Makoviy Pirog&#8221; &#8211; Poppy Seeds Challah Centerpiece Wreath</title>
		<link>/2015/10/russian-recipe-makoviy-pirog-poppy.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/10/russian-recipe-makoviy-pirog-poppy.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 23:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Almonds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cardamom pods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Challah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poppy seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/10/14/russian-recipe-makoviy-pirog-poppy/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Russians love to bake. My childhood home always smelled like sweet dough and we had bakes all year round. But of course fall and winter were special seasons for baking. To the day I still carry that tradition. When the weather starts to cool down and first firewood is put to use, I like to spend my time baking and creating new sweet recipes. Poppy seeds is one of the commonly used baking ingredients in Russian cuisine. Challah is my favorite type of dough, it is simple to make, it&#8217;s tasty and its texture is great. If poppy seeds are too much trouble for you, just make plain Challah wreath and top it with almonds. But I absolutely love poppy seeds here, they bring sweet crunch to this delicious dinner table centerpiece. This recipe is great for holidays and family gatherings. For more Russian recipes, visit Russian Cuisine page.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/10/russian-recipe-makoviy-pirog-poppy.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Rassolnik&#8221; &#8211; Beef Short Rib Soup with Vegetables, Barley &#038; Pickles</title>
		<link>/2015/10/russian-monday-rassolnik-beef-short-rib.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/10/russian-monday-rassolnik-beef-short-rib.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Meat and Poultry Soups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beef Short Rib]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pickles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rassolnik]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/10/05/russian-monday-rassolnik-beef-short-rib/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With great pleasure I am happy to introduce you to one of my favorite soups – pickled soup (or “rassolnik” in Russian). This is traditional soup of peasants and farmers, people working the land &#8211; hearty, tasty and cheap to cook. Today’s “rassolnik” is direct descendant of picked dishes of traditional Russian cuisine, some of which  included pirogue with stuffing soaked in cucumber or any other spicy brine. Four main varieties of “rassolnik” are made either with meat, fish, vegetable or giblets broth and pickles is mandatory ingredient in all of these varieties. For more Russian recipes, visit Russian Cuisine page.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/10/russian-monday-rassolnik-beef-short-rib.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: Warm Potato Salad with Radish &#038; Cucumber, Mustard Dressing</title>
		<link>/2015/09/russian-monday-warm-potato-salad-with.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/09/russian-monday-warm-potato-salad-with.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Main Dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cucumber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Herbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mustard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Potatoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakuska]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/09/28/russian-monday-warm-potato-salad-wi/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In serious Russian cookbooks potato salads always merit to get chapter of their own. This is because potato salad is not just salad with potatoes, like “Vinegrette” or &#8220;Olivier&#8221;, you are already familiar with, but rather whole category of salads, in which potatoes are the leading ingredient. This particular kind of salad does not require young small potatoes (although, I like to use new potatoes for this salad), the important factor is if the kind of potatoes you use would keep their shape after boiling and can be easily cut in cubes or slices that would not break when mixing with other ingredients. Usually it is recommended to boil potatoes unpeeled. It is important to avoid over-boiling, so in order to check readiness you can use fork to poke a potato or two and if you can penetrate them without an effort – your potatoes are ready. For more Russian recipes, visit Russian Cuisine page.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/09/russian-monday-warm-potato-salad-with.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: &#8220;Zavarnoe Koltso&#8221; &#8211; Choux Pastry Rings with Sweet Farmer Cheese Butter Cream</title>
		<link>/2015/09/russian-monday-zavarnoe-koltso-choux.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/09/russian-monday-zavarnoe-koltso-choux.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Choux pastry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Farmer Cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Puff Ring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanilla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/09/21/russian-monday-zavarnoe-koltso-choux/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I will always remember from time to time, when coming from school, in cold and rainy autumn and winter days, opening the door and immediately smell the baking sweets being made. My fondest memories are of my mother baking “Zavarnie Kolechki” (Choux Pastry Rings). I hope you&#8217;ll enjoy this delicate dessert from my childhood. I wonder what foods and recipes do you remember fondly from childhood, and where are you from? For more Russian recipes, visit Russian Cuisine page. Elegantly light and crisp, choux pastry puffs up during baking to at least double its original size, creating a hollow center, perfect for sweet filling. Choux is one of the easiest pastries to make; follow the instructions and you can’t go wrong.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/09/russian-monday-zavarnoe-koltso-choux.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday; &#8220;Lenivie Vareniki&#8221; &#8211; &#8220;Lazy&#8221; Vanilla Ricotta Dumplings with Whole Wheat Flour</title>
		<link>/2015/05/russian-monday-lenivie-vareniki-lazy.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/05/russian-monday-lenivie-vareniki-lazy.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 07:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dumplings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lemon Zest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ricotta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Semolina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanilla Sugar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vareniki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whole wheat flour]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/05/04/russian-monday-lenivie-vareniki-lazy/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“Lazy” dumplings (or “le-nee-vye va-re-nee-kee” in Russian) are gnocchi-shaped dumplings made by mixing ricotta cheese or farmer cheese with egg and white/wheat flour into a quick dough. It is an easier version for people who don&#8217;t have time to make stuffed dumplings. These are great for breakfast and my mom used to make them for me many times. They can be served in many ways, for example &#8211; with sweet sauce, berries, and cream. If you like to have a savory version, add shredded cheese, fresh green peas and serve them with melted butter or even tomato sauce. I used whole wheat flour for my recipe, but you are welcome to use all-purpose flour, that way your dumplings will come out whiter and lighter.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/05/russian-monday-lenivie-vareniki-lazy.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: Omelet &#8221; po Leningradski&#8221; &#8211; Omelet with Onion, Tomato, Veal &#038; Fresh Herbs</title>
		<link>/2015/04/russian-monday-omelet-po-leningradski.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/04/russian-monday-omelet-po-leningradski.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 23:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cooked meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[omelet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Onion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parsley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tomatoes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/04/27/russian-monday-omelet-po-leningradski/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As you know, I was born and grew up in St. Petersburg (formerly Leningrad). From my childhood memories I remember most popular breakfast of the time &#8211; omelet with onions, tomatoes, any cooked meat and fresh herbs. It was something known to everyone and cooked in great variety of ways. This omelet does not have any “official” name, but I have nicknamed it “po Leningradsky” (“Leningrad omelet”), in honor of my old city. The omelet is fresh, colorful and fulfilling, you can use any leftover cooked meat or cold cuts and it can be done in 15 minutes. It is great breakfast dish in one pan for the whole family. For fresh herbs you can use parsley, dill, cilantro or scallions. Serve it with dark bread toast. For more Russian recipes, visit Russian Cuisine page. Step-by-step photos were taken by my 9 years old son Daniel. Thank you my dear little helper!!! Note: I like to do all my prep work before cooking, that way my omelet is ready in 10-15 minutes. Serves: 3-4 Ingredients: 1 Tbsp. olive oil or grape seed oil 4 plum tomatoes, cut into halves and sliced 1 yellow onion, julienne, cut into thin strips 1 [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/04/russian-monday-omelet-po-leningradski.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: &#8220;Sushki&#8221; &#8211; Sweet Tea Bread, Baked Crunchy Round Snacks</title>
		<link>/2015/04/russian-monday-sushki-sweet-tea-bread.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/04/russian-monday-sushki-sweet-tea-bread.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 23:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baked]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mid-afternoon tea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poppy seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sushki]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/04/06/russian-monday-sushki-sweet-tea-bread/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I use to love these little tea bread when I was a child and I still love them today. I buy them often in a Russian grocery store near by but always had a desire to bake them myself. Sushki are slightly sweet crunchy round pastries/cookies which are served with tea or eaten as a snack. They look like mini bagels but they are very dry and crispy. They are fun to make, actually, our whole family was making them &#8211; that is why our sushki look all different-)) It&#8217;s ok, we had some good time. I like them with poppy seeds, but you can make them plain or top them with sesame seeds as well. For more Russian recipes, visit the Russian Cuisine page. Hope you had a very nice Easter weekend! Illustration by Yelena Strokin]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/04/russian-monday-sushki-sweet-tea-bread.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: &#8220;Romovay Baba&#8221; &#8211; Rum Baba</title>
		<link>/2015/03/russian-monday-romovay-baba-rum-baba.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/03/russian-monday-romovay-baba-rum-baba.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 23:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baba au rhum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking with Julia cookbook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Butter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[childhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mold]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raisins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Romovay Baba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rum Baba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/03/23/russian-monday-romovay-baba-rum-baba/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I was a child we were allowed to go by ourselves to the local food store for simple shopping such as getting bread or milk. Very often in my early age, I had basic grocery shopping as a chore. Our nearby bakery was nothing special. They stocked few varieties of bread, some breakfast pastries, as well as few cakes, were always available, but that was all. But sometimes, if you were lucky to come to the store at the right time, you could find a number of sweet treats behind the glass display. One of such treats was rum baba, soaked in sweet syrup, rum and covered with a white sugar icing. So once in a while, I used to come home from my shopping trip with an extra item. Nobody complained, of course, tea kettle was immediately put on and sweet baba was served regardless what time of the day it was. We have never baked baba at home, so I don&#8217;t have family baba recipe. Recently I have recalled some of my childhood sweet delights and decided to give rum baba a try. I used a recipe from Julia Child’s book and my baba came out just [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/03/russian-monday-romovay-baba-rum-baba.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
