<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Bread &#8211; Cooking Melangery</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/bread/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>from sauté to soufflé</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 22:46:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cropped-Untitled-1-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Bread &#8211; Cooking Melangery</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Homemade Bialys with Goat Cheese and Onions</title>
		<link>/2023/06/homemade-bialys-with-goat-cheese-and-onions.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 22:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bialys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breakfas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goat Cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Homemade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[onions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poppy seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scallions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5568</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Baking sweet or savory breads &#8211; its an act of creation. Bread literally grows from your hands. You bring the dormant yeast to life, knead the flour into the dough, nature it, care for it, and shape it into a loaf, rolls, or braid it, then bake it until its golden brown and smooth outside, chewy and tasty inside. Bread baking is one of the most ancient, most elemental rituals. Before there were molds, loaves were usually round. Before there were ovens, dough was flattened for easier cooking. Today, round and flat loaves are still popular, but bread come in all shapes and sizes, and from all kind of grains. Sardinian bakers make very thin crackling rounds called “fogli di music” (sheets of music); from France we get long, crusty baguettes; in Mexico tortillas are most popular; and the Portuguese are known for their light, puffy sweet bread.&#160; Every bread has a unique history. Originally from Poland, traditionally the bialys are made with sauté onions and poppy seeds. But if you like to indulge yourself, add soft goat cheese on a top and fresh scallions in the dough. Bialys are great toasted with butter or a schemer with cream cheese. [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zucchini Bread with Mint &#038; Pecans</title>
		<link>/2020/12/zucchini-bread-with-mint-pecans.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:11:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cakes, Tarts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pecan Nuts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raisins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanilla extract]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whole wheat flour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zucchini]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5279</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Line a basket or a pretty dish with a napkin and fill it with breakfast bakes &#8211; hot, tender, and a little sweet. Hearty and robust or delicate cake-like, all slices of quick bread have a place on the morning table. Chunky jams and preserves go well with full-flavored bakes, while the more subtle ones need only sweet butter, a little crème fraîche, or perhaps a spoonful of jelly. Some breads, such as those filled with berries, need no accompaniment at all. Quick breads are made from the same type of batter as muffins. They share the same uneven, sometimes cake-like crumb. They are breads usually feel with nuts and cranberries at Christmas, pumpkin puree near Thanksgiving, and zucchini at summer&#8217;s end when the garden is overrun with the squash. Quick breads very often benefit from being made a day ahead and wrapped tightly in foil to mellow their flavor, but I never can wait that long-) Inspired by: &#8220;Ancient Grains for Modern Meals&#8221; by Maria Speck]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rye Sourdough Bread with Raisins</title>
		<link>/2020/05/rye-sourdough-bread-with-raisins.html</link>
					<comments>/2020/05/rye-sourdough-bread-with-raisins.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 20:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Homemade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raisins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rye flour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sourdough]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here are some interesting thoughts where the sourdough came from one of my vintage books by Jeff Smith “The Frugal Gourmet Cooks American”. “Sourdough is probably the oldest form of “raised” or “leavened” bread that we know. While the Egyptians are generally given credit for baking the first raised bread, we must also remember that their claim to this fame occurred just after the Jews had fled Egypt, leaving their leavening behind. They were taught to bake unleavened loaves of bread in the desert. Most likely from the historical events that it was the Jews who brought a wild leavening from the desert, a sourdough, into Egypt, and the Hebrew people taught the Egyptians how to bake raised bread in the first place. In any case, we are all familiar with the biblical lines about a little leaven leavening the whole. The Bible is referring to sourdough, and we have been using these wild yeast forms ever since. There is some evidence that Columbus brought a sourdough starter with him on the ships when he set out for the New World. In the time of Columbus, sourdough was the only kind of yeast available. It was used in this country [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/05/rye-sourdough-bread-with-raisins.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazing Breads that Anyone can Bake</title>
		<link>/2020/03/amazing-breads-that-anyone-can-bake.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 18:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sandwich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whole wheat flour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yeast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=7240</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s a staple in homes across our wide, wonderful world. You toast it. You send it to school in your kids’ lunchboxes. You slap whatever culinary delights tickle your fancy on it, to make a complete meal in record time. Bread truly is an incredible, versatile food. Did you ever consider that you could bake it yourself?&#160; If your answer is &#8220;no&#8221;, that you probobly have some reasons for it. It takes too much time. It’s too complicated. It’s too expensive. This article is here to open your eyes to a new world of delicious possibilities.  You see, with bread becoming a mainstay in many global diets, the laws of supply and demand are doing what they do. Take a stroll down the bread aisle, grab two bags of bread, and you’ll see what I mean. As a community, we eat so much bread that companies are forced to use mass production lines to keep up.&#160; If you want anything more specialized than factory-produced bread, you’ve got to go to the bakery. The thing is, these types of bread are priced as specialty items, too. You can get something handmade if you’re willing to pay extra.&#160; If you’re willing to [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Challah</title>
		<link>/2020/03/challah.html</link>
					<comments>/2020/03/challah.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 02:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Challah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5882</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I always think of challah as Eastern European brioche. It&#8217;s a wonderful golden egg-and-butter bread with a texture only slightly tighter then brioche. Braided challah was very popular at our house back in Russia and I like to keep this tradition and make some weekends and holidays extra special by baking challah myself.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/03/challah.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Irish Barm Brack Bread with Dried Apricots Perfect for St.Patrick&#8217;s Day</title>
		<link>/2016/03/irish-barmbrack-bread-with-dried.html</link>
					<comments>/2016/03/irish-barmbrack-bread-with-dried.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 13:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barmbrack Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[celebration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dried Apricots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[St.Patrick's Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2016/03/16/irish-barmbrack-bread-with-dried/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Barm Brack is a yeast bread with added raisins (I added dried apricots)  &#8211; it is sweeter that standard bread but not as rich as cake. Although, it is traditionally eaten around Halloween, when charms are baked into the dough as part of an ancient fortune-telling ritual, I think it is perfect for those who celebrate St.Patrick’s day. Ireland is the country to inspire you and to make you find new ways to love life. While living in Ireland one can be ever proud of his countrymen. It is impossible not to believe in fairies dancing in the night among hawthorn branches or giants building the road out of hexahedron pillars in the cold sea. It is impossible not to fall in love with these emerald hills serving as year round pastures for cows, with magical mountains of Connemara covered by soft moss or grey limestone pavements of Burren hiding delicate flowers in its clefts, away from the severe Atlantic fogs. May your blessings outnumber The shamrocks that grow, And may trouble avoid you Wherever you go. ~ Irish blessing Few more Irish recipes for a special celebration. Irish Coffee Whisky Marinated Flank Steak Broiled with Mushrooms &#38; Onions Irish [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2016/03/irish-barmbrack-bread-with-dried.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pumpkin Bread with Raisins, Dried Cherries &#038; Pumpkin Seeds</title>
		<link>/2015/10/pumpkin-bread-with-raisins-dried.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/10/pumpkin-bread-with-raisins-dried.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 22:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baked]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cinnamon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dried cherries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dry Yeast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nutmeg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pumpkin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pumpkin seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raisin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/10/28/pumpkin-bread-with-raisins-dried/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Old-fashioned hospitality is at its best when you combine good food with your friends. And what could be more neighborly than to welcome your guests with a special fresh baked pumpkin bread full of flavors and fall&#8217;s vibrant color? inspired by &#8220;Baking with Julia&#8221;]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/10/pumpkin-bread-with-raisins-dried.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: &#8220;Makoviy Pirog&#8221; &#8211; Poppy Seeds Challah Centerpiece Wreath</title>
		<link>/2015/10/russian-recipe-makoviy-pirog-poppy.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/10/russian-recipe-makoviy-pirog-poppy.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 23:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Almonds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cardamom pods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Challah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poppy seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/10/14/russian-recipe-makoviy-pirog-poppy/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Russians love to bake. My childhood home always smelled like sweet dough and we had bakes all year round. But of course fall and winter were special seasons for baking. To the day I still carry that tradition. When the weather starts to cool down and first firewood is put to use, I like to spend my time baking and creating new sweet recipes. Poppy seeds is one of the commonly used baking ingredients in Russian cuisine. Challah is my favorite type of dough, it is simple to make, it&#8217;s tasty and its texture is great. If poppy seeds are too much trouble for you, just make plain Challah wreath and top it with almonds. But I absolutely love poppy seeds here, they bring sweet crunch to this delicious dinner table centerpiece. This recipe is great for holidays and family gatherings. For more Russian recipes, visit Russian Cuisine page.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/10/russian-recipe-makoviy-pirog-poppy.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Garlic Bread with Fresh Herbs Baked in Flower Pots</title>
		<link>/2015/09/garlic-bread-with-fresh-herbs-baked-in.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/09/garlic-bread-with-fresh-herbs-baked-in.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 20:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Autumn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fennel seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flower pots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fresh herbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nova Scotia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/09/15/garlic-bread-with-fresh-herbs-baked-in/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are few things more pleasurable than the aroma and taste of freshly cooked home-made bread. These flower pot loaves are flavored with fresh chives, sage, parsley and garlic. You can use any selection of your favorite herbs. These are the most visually stunning breads and the are perfect for entertaining.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/09/garlic-bread-with-fresh-herbs-baked-in.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cinnamon-Pecan Buns/Rolls with Butter Frosting</title>
		<link>/2015/04/cinnamon-pecan-bunsrolls-with-butter.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/04/cinnamon-pecan-bunsrolls-with-butter.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 22:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brown sugar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Butter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cinnamon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cocoa powder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frosting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pecan Nuts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rolls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanilla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yeast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/04/20/cinnamon-pecan-bunsrolls-with-butter/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[These cinnamon buns/rolls are very special, sweet, gooey and irresistible. You fill the dough with sugary pecans, mixed with cinnamon, butter, and cocoa powder, that produces beautiful, buttery layers. These bear no resemblance to anything store-bought. &#8220;It&#8217;s spring fever. That is what the name of it is. And when you&#8217;ve got it, you want—oh, you don&#8217;t quite know what it is you do want, but it just fairly makes your heart ache, you want it so!”&#160;― Mark Twain]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/04/cinnamon-pecan-bunsrolls-with-butter.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Strawberry Scones with Blood Orange Icing</title>
		<link>/2015/03/strawberry-scones-with-blood-orange.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/03/strawberry-scones-with-blood-orange.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 09:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blood Orange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Icing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strawberry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanilla Sugar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/03/20/strawberry-scones-with-blood-orange/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Scones resemble biscuits, and indeed might be considered their British cousins. They are common-place on the tea table but being inherently rebellious, people from other countries find them inviting on the breakfast table as well. Scones are simple to put together. They are generally heavier than biscuits and often are studded with fresh and dried fruits, ginger or made from nutritious oats. A hot scone eaten as the British do, with a dollop of crème fraîche or Devonshire cream and some chunky berry preserves, is a taste treat not to be missed on either side of the Atlantic. These easy-to-make, substantial strawberry scones are simply splendid in the morning with a steaming cup of coffee. Have a sweet weekend!!!]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/03/strawberry-scones-with-blood-orange.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 Recipes for St.Patrick&#8217;s Day to Try</title>
		<link>/2015/03/6-recipes-for-stpatricks-day-to-try.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/03/6-recipes-for-stpatricks-day-to-try.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beef, Lamb, Veal, Pork]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cakes, Tarts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meat & Poultry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chocolate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cupcake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guinness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irish Coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irish Cream liquor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irish Soda Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[St.Patrick's Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/03/15/6-recipes-for-stpatricks-day-to-try/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have a small collection of Irish recipes for all occasions &#8211; a hearty family supper, a traditional St.Patrick&#8217;s Day party, or a special celebration. I hope you&#8217;ll find your favorite! Beef and Guinness Pie with Chanterelle Mushrooms Irish Soda Bread Irish Coffee Brown Soda Bread with Buckwheat Flour &#38; Molasses Guinness Stout Ginger Cake Irish Cream Coffee Cupcakes &#38; Marshmallow Top]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/03/6-recipes-for-stpatricks-day-to-try.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Homemade Pita Bread</title>
		<link>/2015/03/homemade-pita-bread.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/03/homemade-pita-bread.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 22:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Homemade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hummus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Simple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snack]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/03/06/homemade-pita-bread/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pita Bread also is known as pocket bread and made with white or whole wheat flour. Pita can be cut into wedges and served with meals or appetizers, especially dips, or is halved crosswise, and the resulting pockets may be filled with various vegetables, salads to make a sandwich. We love to serve it with traditional hummus, fresh herbs, and cucumbers. Pitas are pretty amazing just warm from the oven with a drizzle of your favorite oil. For this pita recipe, I made my own flour by grinding soft white wheat.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/03/homemade-pita-bread.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brown Soda Bread with  Buckwheat Flour &#038; Molasses</title>
		<link>/2015/03/brown-soda-bread-with-buckwheat-flour.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/03/brown-soda-bread-with-buckwheat-flour.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 12:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buckwheat flour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buttermilk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irish Soda Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Molasses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[St.Patrick's Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Traditional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whole wheat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/03/02/brown-soda-bread-with-buckwheat-flour/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Soda bread has long been a staple in Ireland. It is a bread made without yeast because baking soda mixed with buttermilk is used as a leavening agent. A cross is cut into the top of the bread to help it rise and, according to Irish folklore, to either ward off evil or let the fairies out. This bread is different from soda bread I baked a couple of years ago, it is more rustic and has earthy flavors. I like it that way, it brings me to an old Irish pub, where you can have a mutton stew with bread and butter and a pint of Guinness.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/03/brown-soda-bread-with-buckwheat-flour.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spicy Orange Honey Quick Bread</title>
		<link>/2014/12/spicy-orange-honey-quick-bread.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/12/spicy-orange-honey-quick-bread.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anise star]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cardamom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cinnamon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coconut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orange zest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rye flour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanilla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whole wheat flour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Winter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/12/05/spicy-orange-honey-quick-bread/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whenever the holiday season comes around, I&#8217;m always in a yearning mood for a Spicy Orange Honey Quick Bread. There is something about the aroma that fills the house on a cold night, and the combined savory and delicate sweetness of the buckwheat honey, cinnamon, star anise and the nutmeg that compliments just about every hot drink &#8211; &#160;from a cup of tea or coffee, to a cup of cocoa or even a steaming glass of sangria &#8211; to be enjoyed alone or better yet, with your friends and loved ones by the crackling fire.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/12/spicy-orange-honey-quick-bread.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rye Bread with Flax, Amaranth, Quinoa &#038; Sesame Seeds</title>
		<link>/2014/11/rye-bread-with-flax-amaranth-quinoa.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/11/rye-bread-with-flax-amaranth-quinoa.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 09:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amaranth seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flax Seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quinoa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rye flour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sesame seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yeast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/11/04/rye-bread-with-flax-amaranth-quinoa/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Home-baked bread speaks to us of the warmth of the hearth and home. It conjures up bustling kitchens, flour-dusted work counters, large bowls covered with dishtowels, ovens yearning for bread pans filled with plum, yielding dough. The baked bread, which permeates the house with its indescribable aroma, is beautifully browned, its crust crisp or softly elastic. There it sits, cooling on a wire rack, waiting for the time to be right to slice it and spread it with pale creamery butter and maybe a spoonful of the apple butter.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/11/rye-bread-with-flax-amaranth-quinoa.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rustic Chocolate &#038; Vanilla Bread</title>
		<link>/2014/10/rustic-chocolate-vanilla-bread.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/10/rustic-chocolate-vanilla-bread.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 22:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Autumn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Butter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chocolate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sugar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanilla]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/10/22/rustic-chocolate-vanilla-bread/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the familiar sweet aroma fills the house, no one will be able to resist a slice of this dense, chocolate bread. Breakfast time? Serve the bread at room temperature or toasted, with butter or, for a special treat, with your favorite jam. Delicious Autumn! My very soul is wedded to it, And if I was a bird, Seeking the successive autumns. George Eliot]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/10/rustic-chocolate-vanilla-bread.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
