<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Recipes &#8211; Cooking Melangery</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/recipes/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>from sauté to soufflé</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 22:44:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cropped-Untitled-1-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Recipes &#8211; Cooking Melangery</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Fried Brown Rice with Vegetables &#038; Eggs</title>
		<link>/2021/04/fried-brown-rice-with-vegetables-eggs.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 01:03:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brown Rice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carrots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Herbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Side Dish]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5792</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rice is a staple food throughout much of China and Asia and other places. White and brown plain boiled rice is a useful accompaniment that goes well with a wide variety of dishes, it is easy to combine rice with vegetables, eggs and a range of flavorings and spices to create a rather more special meal. There are many versions of this dish, all of which make use of leftover rice. Ingredients vary according to what is in season. Make sure the rice is cold before attempting to fry it, as warm rice will become soggy. Use rice with a fairly firm texture. Ideally, raw rice should be soaked in water for a short time before cooking.]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Healthy Recipes for a Spring Cleanse</title>
		<link>/2021/02/healthy-recipes-for-a-spring-cleanse.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 22:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salads]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=7284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Easy Steps for a Happy Gut Today, we know that our gut flora, a microbiome population as it is also known as, has a huge impact on our health and our risk of disease. In fact, leading researchers in the field say they can get much more information about your health from assessing your gut flora than some other tests. Each one of us is host to about a pound-and-a-half of gut bacteria made up of over 600 different bacterial families (with each family often having dozens of bacterial strains). The more diverse our gut bacteria population is, the better for our health. A small and limited variety of gut bacteria increases the risk of autoimmune diseases, cancer, heart disease, diabetes, multiple sclerosis, fibromyalgia and obesity. There are several ways to improve the makeup of your gut flora. Read on to find out more. A second brain Because some gut bacteria affect the production of neurotransmitters in the brain, the composition of our gut bacteria also has an effect on our mood, which has a knock-on effect on conditions such as depression and anxiety, to name just a couple.  Inflammation caused by allergies or food intolerances can also affect gut [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Challah</title>
		<link>/2020/03/challah.html</link>
					<comments>/2020/03/challah.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 02:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Challah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5882</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I always think of challah as Eastern European brioche. It&#8217;s a wonderful golden egg-and-butter bread with a texture only slightly tighter then brioche. Braided challah was very popular at our house back in Russia and I like to keep this tradition and make some weekends and holidays extra special by baking challah myself.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/03/challah.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicken of the Woods Cream of Mushroom Soup</title>
		<link>/2019/10/chicken-of-the-woods-cream-of-mushroom-soup.html</link>
					<comments>/2019/10/chicken-of-the-woods-cream-of-mushroom-soup.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 01:27:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetable and Grain Soups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buckwheat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicken of the woods mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foraging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wild]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is a hearty soup that captures the flavor of the Chicken of the woods. It goes best with a full-bodied Zinfandel for a midday lunch! Laetiporus sulphureous known as Chicken-of-the-Woods The common name of this a fungus derives from the fact that, when cooked, this mushroom has the texture of fresh chicken breast. The fungus is one of a larger group of fungi known as polypores &#8211; similar to boletes in that the underside of the cap is composed of pores rather than gills. In most cases polyphonies are inedible because of their woody texture. Some, however, are quite good to eat, and the chicken of the woods is among the best known. It is also known as the sulfur mushroom because the underside of the cap is a bright yellow color. The top side is red-orange, which makes it very easy to identify. These fungi can be seen growing out of fallen and rotting trees from summer to late fall. Older specimens take a long time to cook because of their woody texture. Younger specimens take just a short time to make them soft and chewable. The part of the fungus farthest from the base is the most [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/10/chicken-of-the-woods-cream-of-mushroom-soup.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Maple Roasted Brussels Sprouts with Cumin-Scented Quinoa &#038; Pecans</title>
		<link>/2019/09/maple-roasted-brussels-sprouts-with-cumin-scented-quinoa-pecans.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 01:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brussels Sprouts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cilantro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dinner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gluten-free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maple syrup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pecan Nuts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pomegranate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quinoa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roasted]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Side Dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetarian]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5283</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The crunchiness and superb simplicity of roasted Brussel sprouts are underrated. They are a delicacy. Combine this humble vegetable with ancient quinoa and wait for those flavors to merge into a divine union. Serve with pan-fried fish or grilled chicken.]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Autumn Recipe with Roasted Vegetables, Lima Beans &#038; Buckwheat- Florida Trip (Part Two)</title>
		<link>/2018/11/autumn-recipe-with-roasted-vegetables-lima-beans-buckwheat-florida-trip-part-two.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 22:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Autumn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buckwheat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cauliflower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lima beans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roasted pumpkin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=3767</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I had some lovely time with my dear friends and clients in Winter Park, Florida at the beginning of September. My photography exhibition was taking place at AXIOM gallery while I visited Jeff and Bryan (the owners of The Ancient Olive store) at the same time. They were the first people who loved my still life art photography and we have worked together on branding for their stores. I was so happy to see their shopping bags, business cards and company stationery beautified by my art. Jeffrey and Bryan are very dear to me and finally, we got to meet and spend some time together. There is so much to do in Winter Park, but the town’s most attractive place is their store. The Ancient Olive carries a boutique assortment of amazing cheeses, jams, mustards, sauces, oils, and vinegar. The store itself is absolutely lovely and that extends to the people who work there. I have tasted many delicious gourmet foods my only regret was having an only small suitcase with me 😊 Regardless, my family was happy with the gifts from the shop, the only problem &#8211; it was all gone in no time-)) I have created this recipe [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: Buckwheat Soup with Cauliflower &#038; Turmeric &#8211; Florida Trip (Part One)</title>
		<link>/2018/09/russian-monday-buckwheat-soup-with-cauliflower-turmeric-florida-trip-part-one.html</link>
					<comments>/2018/09/russian-monday-buckwheat-soup-with-cauliflower-turmeric-florida-trip-part-one.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 03:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetable and Grain Soups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buckwheat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cauliflower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Herbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muchrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Turmeric]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=3614</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the weather turns colder and fall steps in, &#8220;cold weather soups&#8221; are an indispensable part of the menu. I would like to share with you one of my favorites &#8211; buckwheat soup!&#160;It is filling, super healthy and delicious. When it is raining or freezing outside, what else is better than to snuggle on the couch in your PJs, with a warm blanket, good book or film and a huge bowl of warm yummy soup? For me personally, soups are good in any weather &#8211; &#160;lentil soup, chicken soup, potato carrot, and definitely buckwheat soup are on my &#8220;short list&#8221;. But first &#8211; a little story. Today is a very special Russian Monday. One week ago, I was visiting my dear friends in Winter Park, Florida. They are also huge fans of my blog and my fine art photography. And it happened to be that Russian Monday is their favorite chapter on my blog. One thing leads to another and we found ourselves cooking Russian food for sixteen people for Monday evening. The menu was simple but creative. Our starters were roasted marrow bones with pickled onions, small sandwiches with&#160;fish, caviar, and vegetables, potato salad &#8220;Olivier&#8221;, and amazing cheese tray [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/09/russian-monday-buckwheat-soup-with-cauliflower-turmeric-florida-trip-part-one.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Buckwheat Waffles Sweet and Savory</title>
		<link>/2018/03/buckwheat-waffles-sweet-and-savory.html</link>
					<comments>/2018/03/buckwheat-waffles-sweet-and-savory.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 15:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buckwheat flour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cast iron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grain mill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pleasant Hill Grain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Savory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waffles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2018/03/23/buckwheat-waffles-sweet-and-savory/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My kids love waffles &#8211; making them in a cast iron waffle-maker on the stove is a very unique experience. Waffles come out very crispy outside and nice and soft inside with the earthy aroma of home ground flour. When I was a child I spent a few of my summer breaks with my aunt’s family in a small Russian village. The house they lived in was made of logs, had a huge wood-burning clay oven, a barn for animals, a beautiful garden with green peas and carrots, an orchard with apple trees and of course a banya &#8211; the Russian sauna. Although I was not happy back then to spend my summers with cows and chickens, now as I look back, I can truly say that was the best time of my life and I miss the simple life in the country. I used to wake up every day smelling the aroma of freshly baked bread and other breakfast pastry my aunt baked in the morning. She got up very early at sunrise, with the rooster’s crow. She milked the cow, fed the animals and started to burn wood in the oven to warm up the house and cook the food. [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/03/buckwheat-waffles-sweet-and-savory.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Popcorn with ”Buffalo Wings” Red Hot Sauce</title>
		<link>/2017/12/popcorn-with-buffalo-wings-red-hot-sauce.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 20:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buffalo Wings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Butter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hot sauce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Popcorn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Summer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=4307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>4 Exciting Ways to Use Coffee in Recipe</title>
		<link>/2017/07/4-exciting-ways-to-use-coffee-in-recipe.html</link>
					<comments>/2017/07/4-exciting-ways-to-use-coffee-in-recipe.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 21:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beverage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irish Coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smoothie]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2017/07/17/4-exciting-ways-to-use-coffee-in-recipe/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Think coffee is just a beverage? If so, you are missing out on the wide array of unique dishes you can create using coffee. From breakfast all the way to dessert, this much-loved drink can add extraordinary flavor to many of your favorite foods. Coffee is also highly versatile, making it an exceptional pairing with a range of other flavors. If you’ve been looking to add a bit of excitement to mealtime, check out several of the unique ways you can use coffee in recipes. Grilled and baked meats Although it may sound unconventional at first, coffee can add robust flavor to all varieties of meat. You can use freshly ground coffee on ribeye, turkey, roasts, pork, lamb, burgers, or any other type of meat you prefer. To properly add the flavor, you can create either a dry rub or a marinade. If you enjoy a bit of a kick to your food, feel free to add your favorite seasoning (such as cumin or cayenne) to complement the coffee rub or marinade. Dessert If you previously believed that the only dessert that could be made using coffee is tiramisu, you might be shocked to find out how many desserts you [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2017/07/4-exciting-ways-to-use-coffee-in-recipe.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Orange Apricot Biscotti with Pistachios &#038; Hazelnuts &#8211; Perfect Cookies for the Mothers Day</title>
		<link>/2016/05/orange-apricot-biscotti-with-pistachios.html</link>
					<comments>/2016/05/orange-apricot-biscotti-with-pistachios.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cookies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biscotti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dried Apricots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hazelnut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mothers Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pistachio nuts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2016/05/06/orange-apricot-biscotti-with-pistachios/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My new Still live with flowers and butterflies &#8211; prints are available for sale! When you are a mother, you are never really alone in your thoughts. A mother always has to think twice, once for herself and once for her child. — SOPHIA LOREN Happy Mothers Day!!! Great to have these tasty crispy cookies on hand when guests stop by during the Mothers day, these biscotti also make lovely gifts. You can substitute dried apricots for the cherries, if you like. Please enjoy another video from Cooking Melangery team.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2016/05/orange-apricot-biscotti-with-pistachios.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cheese &#038; Garlic Salad</title>
		<link>/2016/03/russian-monday-cheese-garlic-salad.html</link>
					<comments>/2016/03/russian-monday-cheese-garlic-salad.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zakusky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appetizer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spring]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2016/03/26/russian-monday-cheese-garlic-salad/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Although, today is not a Monday but I feel this post is very appropriate for Easter. It was my husband’s idea to make a post about this salad. He loves it and remembers eating it back home on every holiday. The dish is very simple, but I am sure you will love the taste. Pick your favorite cheese or combination of cheeses. Amount of garlic is totally up to you, our family loves a lot of it-)) Also you can serve it on top of cherry or plum tomatoes, and fresh spring herbs would be a wonderful addition. Russian Orthodox Easter Day will be on May 1 this year. But I would love to wish Happy Easter to everyone who celebrates it this Sunday! Awake, thou wintry earth &#8211; Fling off thy sadness! Fair vernal flowers, laugh forth Your ancient gladness! ~Thomas Blackburn, &#8220;An Easter Hymn&#8221;]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2016/03/russian-monday-cheese-garlic-salad.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roasted Spiral Root Vegetable Salad with Citrus Dressing</title>
		<link>/2016/03/roasted-spiral-root-vegetable-salad.html</link>
					<comments>/2016/03/roasted-spiral-root-vegetable-salad.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 17:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Salads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dressing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garlic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lemon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oxo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Root Vegetable Salad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sesame seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spiral]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2016/03/22/roasted-spiral-root-vegetable-salad/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earthy beets, rutabagas and slightly sweet carrots are a winning combination, especially when they are tossed with a citrus dressing with the bright flavors of orange and lemon juice. This salad is also tasty if a green apple spirals are tossed with the roasted vegetables. I always wanted to use a spiralizer to make colorful salads. Spring is here and I think the time has come to get stuffed with healthy food. I got the GoodGrips Spiralizer from OXO and today my son and I had so much fun twisting the vegetables! My big helper liked my “spaghetti” and he was happy to help me out with a preparation and tasting. Note: This post is being sponsored by OXO. I did not receive any compensation for this post, I received OXO GoodGrips Spiralizer.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2016/03/roasted-spiral-root-vegetable-salad.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Irish Barm Brack Bread with Dried Apricots Perfect for St.Patrick&#8217;s Day</title>
		<link>/2016/03/irish-barmbrack-bread-with-dried.html</link>
					<comments>/2016/03/irish-barmbrack-bread-with-dried.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 13:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barmbrack Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[celebration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dried Apricots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[St.Patrick's Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2016/03/16/irish-barmbrack-bread-with-dried/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Barm Brack is a yeast bread with added raisins (I added dried apricots)  &#8211; it is sweeter that standard bread but not as rich as cake. Although, it is traditionally eaten around Halloween, when charms are baked into the dough as part of an ancient fortune-telling ritual, I think it is perfect for those who celebrate St.Patrick’s day. Ireland is the country to inspire you and to make you find new ways to love life. While living in Ireland one can be ever proud of his countrymen. It is impossible not to believe in fairies dancing in the night among hawthorn branches or giants building the road out of hexahedron pillars in the cold sea. It is impossible not to fall in love with these emerald hills serving as year round pastures for cows, with magical mountains of Connemara covered by soft moss or grey limestone pavements of Burren hiding delicate flowers in its clefts, away from the severe Atlantic fogs. May your blessings outnumber The shamrocks that grow, And may trouble avoid you Wherever you go. ~ Irish blessing Few more Irish recipes for a special celebration. Irish Coffee Whisky Marinated Flank Steak Broiled with Mushrooms &#38; Onions Irish [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2016/03/irish-barmbrack-bread-with-dried.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Whisky Marinated Flank Steak Broiled with Mushrooms &#038; Onions</title>
		<link>/2016/03/whisky-marinated-flank-steak-broiled.html</link>
					<comments>/2016/03/whisky-marinated-flank-steak-broiled.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 23:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beef, Lamb, Veal, Pork]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dinner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flank Steak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magazine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marinade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Onion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[publications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[St.Patrick's Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whisky]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2016/03/10/whisky-marinated-flank-steak-broiled/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you celebrate St. Patrick’s day here is a recipe you will not regret to cook. Tasty and absolutely stress free dish. Very few ingredients are needed and only few minutes takes to prepare it. Please enjoy our second video. I am looking forward to your comments. I would love to share with you one more magazine – February/March issue of “Home + Table”. It is dedicated to food and I am so proud of my work on a cover. Please check out few more recipes published inside.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2016/03/whisky-marinated-flank-steak-broiled.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blini &#8211; Vanilla Crepes with Berries</title>
		<link>/2016/03/russian-monday-blini-vanilla-crepes.html</link>
					<comments>/2016/03/russian-monday-blini-vanilla-crepes.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crepes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fruit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magazine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maslenitsa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[publications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Still Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanilla extract]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2016/03/07/russian-monday-blini-vanilla-crepes/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“Maslenitsa” is a Russian carnival week originating from pre-Christian times. It was celebrated around spring solstice and was dedicated to the boy-Sun named Xors becoming a man-Sun named Yarilo. The main dish of the holiday week are pancakes (or “blini” in Russian) in all their varieties. Their round shape symbolizes the Sun. Later on, after Christianity came to Russia, the holidays fell on the Great Lent, hence the decision was made to move the celebration right before the fasting. During Maslenitsa, older people were using a chance to share their wisdom with the youth by puzzling them with this riddle: “Maslenitsa is forty Grandmothers granddaughter, thirty Brothers sister, three mothers and one father&#8217;s daughter.” The answer to this riddle was an explanation of the sacred knowledge of the structure of the universe the elders believed in. For more information about &#8220;Maslenitsa&#8221; you can read here and here. My new still life &#8220;Long Winter&#8221;- prints are available for sale. Swedish magazine &#8220;La Prestige&#8221; has published my interview in their February issue. They have included 6 pages of Russian cuisine recipes from my &#8220;Russian Monday&#8221; collection featuring my photography. I am very happy to bring this information to my readers in Europe and everywhere else in the [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2016/03/russian-monday-blini-vanilla-crepes.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Victoria Sandwich &#8211; Get ready for Downton Abbey&#8217;s final episode this Sunday!</title>
		<link>/2016/03/victoria-sandwich-get-ready-for-downton.html</link>
					<comments>/2016/03/victoria-sandwich-get-ready-for-downton.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 14:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cakes, Tarts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[After-dinner dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Downton Abbey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raspberry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Victoria Sandwich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whipped cream]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2016/03/03/victoria-sandwich-get-ready-for-downton/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America&#8217;s love affair with the show about the lives and loves of family and servants in an aristocratic home across the pond is coming to an end as the series Downtown Abbey wraps it&#8217;s sixth and final season. We&#8217;ve been treated to melodrama of the highest order, with fast-paced plots, richly drawn characters and even more richly drawn costumes.  Oh, those costumes!  There was even a traveling exhibit here in the states of costumes and jewelry from the show. We&#8217;ve all had fun getting to know the Crawley family and their servants; watching them live life and some of them rather suddenly be taken in death. We&#8217;ve watched as characters have traveled, moved, married and remarried. We&#8217;ve seen some of them grow and change and others watch as the world changes around them. photos from pbs How will we say goodbye to so many characters who, thanks to writer Julian Fellowes, have delighted us so well for so long?! Almost everyone has a favorite quote from the dowager Countess with her kind heart but sharp tongue and even sharper wit! Downton Abbey has also been a feast for the eyes with, not just the gorgeous period costumes but richly beautiful [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2016/03/victoria-sandwich-get-ready-for-downton.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
