<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Breakfast &#8211; Cooking Melangery</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/breakfast/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>from sauté to soufflé</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 22:46:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cropped-Untitled-1-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Breakfast &#8211; Cooking Melangery</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Homemade Bialys with Goat Cheese and Onions</title>
		<link>/2023/06/homemade-bialys-with-goat-cheese-and-onions.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 22:46:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bialys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breakfas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goat Cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Homemade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[onions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poppy seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scallions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5568</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Baking sweet or savory breads &#8211; its an act of creation. Bread literally grows from your hands. You bring the dormant yeast to life, knead the flour into the dough, nature it, care for it, and shape it into a loaf, rolls, or braid it, then bake it until its golden brown and smooth outside, chewy and tasty inside. Bread baking is one of the most ancient, most elemental rituals. Before there were molds, loaves were usually round. Before there were ovens, dough was flattened for easier cooking. Today, round and flat loaves are still popular, but bread come in all shapes and sizes, and from all kind of grains. Sardinian bakers make very thin crackling rounds called “fogli di music” (sheets of music); from France we get long, crusty baguettes; in Mexico tortillas are most popular; and the Portuguese are known for their light, puffy sweet bread.&#160; Every bread has a unique history. Originally from Poland, traditionally the bialys are made with sauté onions and poppy seeds. But if you like to indulge yourself, add soft goat cheese on a top and fresh scallions in the dough. Bialys are great toasted with butter or a schemer with cream cheese. [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rye Sourdough Bread with Raisins</title>
		<link>/2020/05/rye-sourdough-bread-with-raisins.html</link>
					<comments>/2020/05/rye-sourdough-bread-with-raisins.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 20:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Homemade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raisins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rye flour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sourdough]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here are some interesting thoughts where the sourdough came from one of my vintage books by Jeff Smith “The Frugal Gourmet Cooks American”. “Sourdough is probably the oldest form of “raised” or “leavened” bread that we know. While the Egyptians are generally given credit for baking the first raised bread, we must also remember that their claim to this fame occurred just after the Jews had fled Egypt, leaving their leavening behind. They were taught to bake unleavened loaves of bread in the desert. Most likely from the historical events that it was the Jews who brought a wild leavening from the desert, a sourdough, into Egypt, and the Hebrew people taught the Egyptians how to bake raised bread in the first place. In any case, we are all familiar with the biblical lines about a little leaven leavening the whole. The Bible is referring to sourdough, and we have been using these wild yeast forms ever since. There is some evidence that Columbus brought a sourdough starter with him on the ships when he set out for the New World. In the time of Columbus, sourdough was the only kind of yeast available. It was used in this country [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/05/rye-sourdough-bread-with-raisins.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Challah</title>
		<link>/2020/03/challah.html</link>
					<comments>/2020/03/challah.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 02:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Challah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5882</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I always think of challah as Eastern European brioche. It&#8217;s a wonderful golden egg-and-butter bread with a texture only slightly tighter then brioche. Braided challah was very popular at our house back in Russia and I like to keep this tradition and make some weekends and holidays extra special by baking challah myself.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/03/challah.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Baked Oat Squares with Flax Seeds, Pecans and Berries</title>
		<link>/2019/04/baked-oat-squares-with-flax-seeds-pecans-and-berries.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[egg free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flax Seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pecan Nuts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soy free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanilla extract]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=5563</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This recipe is perfectly sweet, filled with oats, crunchy nuts, flax seeds, fresh berries, and fragrant vanilla, and delicious served cold on a next day. A healthy make-ahead breakfast for busy mornings. To grind the flax seeds, pour it into a blender and blend it for 3-5 minutes or until it&#8217;s ground to your liking. For the small amount, you can grind the flax seeds using a coffee grinder.]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amaranth &#038; Steel Cut Oats Porridge with Nuts &#038; Fruits</title>
		<link>/2019/01/amaranth-steel-cut-oats-porridge-with-nuts-fruits.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasta, Rice, Grains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[almond butter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Almond milk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amaranth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chia seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dairy free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flax Seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hemp seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steel cut oats]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=4821</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A valuable source of fiber and nutrients, grains have long been a vital part of man&#8217;s diet. They have been ground into flour for baking since ancient times, and for just as long have been eaten as a hot cereal &#8211; also called mush or gruel. Grains are the dried seeds of grass-like plans. The most familiar are wheat, rice, oats, corn, rye, barley, buckwheat, and millet. All can be eaten hot as a cereal by boiling them. Oats are usually steamed to soften them and then rolled into flaky particles. The only difference between old-fashioned and quick oats is the thickness and size of the flakes. Steel-cut oats, also called Scotch or Irish oatmeal, are small-cut oat grains with a nuttier flavor then rolled oats. I like to use them a lot for my porridges. Amaranth (amaranthus caudatus) is a gluten-free, pseudo-cereal seed with an earthy, grassy flavor, similar to beets. Amaranth seeds can be cooked into porridge, ground into flour, popped or flaked. As a complete protein (containing 18 amino acids), amaranth was an energizing staple for the Aztecs and Mayans who used it to make tortillas, atole and sweets. This tiny seed is a rich source of calcium, iron, [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Smoothie Bowl with Beets, Avocado and Berries</title>
		<link>/2018/08/smoothie-bowl-with-beets-avocado-and-berries.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 02:36:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avocado]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chia seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pine Nuts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Simple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strawberry]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/?p=3352</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you love beets as much as I do that this recipe is definitely for you. It&#8217;s a healthy Paleo + Vegan breakfast or snack, made with only a few ingredients. With strawberries, blackberries, banana, avocado, beets and chia seeds this smoothie bowl is just what you need to power up for the day.]]></description>
		
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Buckwheat Waffles Sweet and Savory</title>
		<link>/2018/03/buckwheat-waffles-sweet-and-savory.html</link>
					<comments>/2018/03/buckwheat-waffles-sweet-and-savory.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 15:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buckwheat flour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cast iron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grain mill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pleasant Hill Grain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Savory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waffles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2018/03/23/buckwheat-waffles-sweet-and-savory/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My kids love waffles &#8211; making them in a cast iron waffle-maker on the stove is a very unique experience. Waffles come out very crispy outside and nice and soft inside with the earthy aroma of home ground flour. When I was a child I spent a few of my summer breaks with my aunt’s family in a small Russian village. The house they lived in was made of logs, had a huge wood-burning clay oven, a barn for animals, a beautiful garden with green peas and carrots, an orchard with apple trees and of course a banya &#8211; the Russian sauna. Although I was not happy back then to spend my summers with cows and chickens, now as I look back, I can truly say that was the best time of my life and I miss the simple life in the country. I used to wake up every day smelling the aroma of freshly baked bread and other breakfast pastry my aunt baked in the morning. She got up very early at sunrise, with the rooster’s crow. She milked the cow, fed the animals and started to burn wood in the oven to warm up the house and cook the food. [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/03/buckwheat-waffles-sweet-and-savory.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>4 Exciting Ways to Use Coffee in Recipe</title>
		<link>/2017/07/4-exciting-ways-to-use-coffee-in-recipe.html</link>
					<comments>/2017/07/4-exciting-ways-to-use-coffee-in-recipe.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 21:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beverage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irish Coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smoothie]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2017/07/17/4-exciting-ways-to-use-coffee-in-recipe/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Think coffee is just a beverage? If so, you are missing out on the wide array of unique dishes you can create using coffee. From breakfast all the way to dessert, this much-loved drink can add extraordinary flavor to many of your favorite foods. Coffee is also highly versatile, making it an exceptional pairing with a range of other flavors. If you’ve been looking to add a bit of excitement to mealtime, check out several of the unique ways you can use coffee in recipes. Grilled and baked meats Although it may sound unconventional at first, coffee can add robust flavor to all varieties of meat. You can use freshly ground coffee on ribeye, turkey, roasts, pork, lamb, burgers, or any other type of meat you prefer. To properly add the flavor, you can create either a dry rub or a marinade. If you enjoy a bit of a kick to your food, feel free to add your favorite seasoning (such as cumin or cayenne) to complement the coffee rub or marinade. Dessert If you previously believed that the only dessert that could be made using coffee is tiramisu, you might be shocked to find out how many desserts you [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2017/07/4-exciting-ways-to-use-coffee-in-recipe.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eggs en Cocotte with Mushrooms &#038; Green Peas</title>
		<link>/2015/03/eggs-en-cocotte-with-mushrooms-green.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/03/eggs-en-cocotte-with-mushrooms-green.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 23:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[en cocotte]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fresh herbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Green Peas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mushrooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/03/30/eggs-en-cocotte-with-mushrooms-green/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A cocotte is a small round or oval dish in which food is cooked and served &#8211; a ramekin or individual casserole. It may be made of fireproof china, tempered glass, earthenware, porcelain, cast iron, copper, or stainless steel. The food cooked and served in such dishes is usually called &#8220;en cocotte&#8221;. I have another recipe which was cooked in cocotte cups &#8211; Mushroom Julien en Cocotte. How to cook eggs en cocotte &#8211; basic recipe: The dishes should be warmed and buttered before the eggs are put in. Break 1 egg into each dish and place the dishes in a shallow pan of hot water. Cook over surface heat 2 to 3 minutes, never allowing the water to boil. Cover the dishes with foil or a baking sheet and finish cooking in a preheated slow oven (325F) &#8211; about 3 to 4 minutes. The whites should be firm and the yolks soft. Allow 1 egg per serving. A tablespoon of heavy cream or chicken stock for extra flavor may be put in each dish. Add eggs and sprinkle with salt and pepper.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/03/eggs-en-cocotte-with-mushrooms-green.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday on Saturday: &#8220;Oladushky&#8221; &#8211; Honey Yeast Blini (Pancakes, Blintzes)</title>
		<link>/2015/02/russian-monday-on-saturday-oladushky.html</link>
					<comments>/2015/02/russian-monday-on-saturday-oladushky.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 14:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bleen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crepes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maslenitsa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pancakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Traditional]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2015/02/21/russian-monday-on-saturday-oladushky/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Winter farewell is a time of awakening; the beginning of new life. Since ancient times, people have enjoyed this time of the year. Festivals and carnivals are held all over the world: Chinese New Year, Venice Carnival, a holiday of the trees &#8211; Tu B’Shvat in Israel, Mardi Gras, even Groundhog Day, which was brought to America from Germany, and one of the oldest Russian holidays &#8211; Maslenitsa. Maslenitsa lasts a week; it is full of fun and joy. The main attribute of the carnival is blintzes. All week in every home, housewives cook pancakes for their families and guests. Blyn (pronounced “bleen” – the Russian word for pancake) &#8211; the symbol of the sun, which is gaining strength with each passing day, warms the earth and gives life. Every day of the carnival has its own purpose. The first day &#8211; a greeting of Maslenitsa. On this day, the first blyn is carried out of the house for ancestors who have already past away. It is believed that they see the sun first, as they are above this world. In later times, when people become poorer, the first blyn is given to the beggars. On this day people make [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/02/russian-monday-on-saturday-oladushky.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ricotta Pancakes with Berry Coulis &#038; Whipped Cream</title>
		<link>/2014/03/ricotta-pancakes-with-berry-coulis.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/03/ricotta-pancakes-with-berry-coulis.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 07:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cornmeal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fruit Coulis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lemon Zest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pancakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ricotta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanilla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whipped cream]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/03/07/ricotta-pancakes-with-berry-coulis/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m entertaining this weekend, and when one particular friend of mine comes over, I always make sure this is on the menu – my ricotta pancakes with berry coulis is her absolute favorite! If you love a good breakfast and you haven&#8217;t tried this, make it with me. Mixing cornmeal, which is a little gritty, in the batter gives these pancakes just a little crunch. Berry sauce with freshly whipped cream, makes them awfully good.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/03/ricotta-pancakes-with-berry-coulis.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Monday: &#8220;Blinis&#8221; &#8211; Savory Buckwheat Pancakes</title>
		<link>/2014/02/russian-monday-blinis-savory-buckwheat.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/02/russian-monday-blinis-savory-buckwheat.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 08:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast & Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian Monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bliny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buckwheat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caviar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maslenniza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pancakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russian cuisine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Savory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/02/24/russian-monday-blinis-savory-buckwhea/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shrovetide (or “maslenitsa” in Russian) is celebrated in the last week before Christian Orthodox Great Fast, seven weeks before Easter. Shrovetide is the holiday preserved by Slavic peoples from pagan (pre-Christian) times. Those days it was called differently when just like many other nations, ancient Slavs had traditional feast associated with winter wires and meeting of spring. At the time this feast was associated with the name of Veles &#8211; god of fertility and livestock in ancient Slavs pantheon. This holiday represented the awakening of nature from winter sleep and marked the beginning of the work in the fields. Also, the feast table must have been plentiful and very hearty as it was meant to manifest the hope for the harvest year. Time of this holiday has always been cheerful and it was believed those who refuse to be merry would end up living “in bitter trouble” for the rest of the year. After the adoption of Christianity in Russia, this holiday has remained a special time of the year, even though it was considered peoples rather than Church holiday. During 16th century name “maslenitsa” got firmly attached to this fun season which lasts seven days. Church statutes prohibited eating [&#8230;]]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/02/russian-monday-blinis-savory-buckwheat.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Carrot Morning Cakes with Oatmeal Crumb &#8211; Have a Sweet Weekend!</title>
		<link>/2014/01/carrot-morning-cakes-with-oatmeal-crumb.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/01/carrot-morning-cakes-with-oatmeal-crumb.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 10:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cakes, Tarts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carrots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cinnamon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crumbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Morning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oatmeal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orange zest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Streusel Topping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walnut oil]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/01/24/carrot-morning-cakes-with-oatmeal-crumb/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For a simple tasty breakfast, try this old-time country style recipe. Sprinkle these large puffy cakes with sugar and cinnamon for a delectably simple dessert. Inspired by Tomas Keller &#8220;Bouchon Bakery&#8221; recipe.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/01/carrot-morning-cakes-with-oatmeal-crumb.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wheat Bran Morning Cakes with Pears</title>
		<link>/2014/01/wheat-bran-morning-cake-with-pears.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/01/wheat-bran-morning-cake-with-pears.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 12:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cakes, Tarts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flax Seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[granola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Honey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Molasses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Morning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pumpkin seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wheat Bran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whole wheat flour]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/01/15/wheat-bran-morning-cake-with-pears/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Quick breakfast cakes are made from the same type of batter as muffins. They share the same uneven, sometimes cake-like crumb. They are bread we fill with nuts and cranberries at Christmas, pumpkin puree near Thanksgiving, and zucchini at summer&#8217;s end when a garden is overrun with the squash. Full of the goodness of wheat, these wholesome, hearty morning cakes taste wonderful on their own, yet are made even better by stirring a handful of pumpkin seeds and the poached pears into the batter. Inspired by Tomas Keller &#8220;Bouchon Bakery&#8221; recipe.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/01/wheat-bran-morning-cake-with-pears.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quiche Lorraine (Whole Wheat Pastry)</title>
		<link>/2014/01/quiche-lorraine-whole-wheat-pastry.html</link>
					<comments>/2014/01/quiche-lorraine-whole-wheat-pastry.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bacon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eggs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pomegranate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quiche Lorraine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Turkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whole wheat flour]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2014/01/01/quiche-lorraine-whole-wheat-pastry/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This classic quiche has some delightful characteristics that are often forgotten in modern recipes; namely very thin pastry, a creamy, light filling, and smoked bacon. Perfect for brunch, parties or family suppers, this tasty quiche celebrates a timeless combination of cheese and bacon, accompanied by a salad and fresh fruit. It said that the Quiche Lorraine was discovered by a baker in Nancy, France in the 16th century. Initially, it was prepared with ordinary bread dough and was later refined when shortcrust (plain) pastry was used for the base. The main ingredient is smoked bacon, one of the province&#8217;s specialties. Traditionally a cake tin with a 7-inch diameter is lined with pastry and the filling is then poured into the lining. It is made of a mixture of cream and eggs, to which small cubes of smoked bacon, are added. When Quiche Lorraine became popular throughout France, grated cheese which originally was not used, somehow tricked its way into the recipe. The original recipe depended solely on the quality of three basic Lorraine products: butter, eggs, and smoked bacon. The bacon owes its quality to hundreds of years of experience.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/01/quiche-lorraine-whole-wheat-pastry.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rustic Chocolate Banana Bread</title>
		<link>/2013/12/rustic-chocolate-banana-bread.html</link>
					<comments>/2013/12/rustic-chocolate-banana-bread.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 08:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chocolate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cocoa powder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanilla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White Chocolate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2013/12/17/rustic-chocolate-banana-bread/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the familiar sweet aroma fills the house, no one will be able to resist a slice of this dense, moist chocolate banana bread. Breakfast time? Serve the bread at room temperature or toasted, with butter or cream cheese. This Chocolate banana bread lightly flecked with dark and white chocolate.]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/12/rustic-chocolate-banana-bread.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dragon Fruit &#8211; What is it and how to eat it</title>
		<link>/2013/11/dragon-fruit-what-is-it-and-how-to-eat.html</link>
					<comments>/2013/11/dragon-fruit-what-is-it-and-how-to-eat.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yelena Strokin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dragon fruit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lime juice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Refreshing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.melangery.com/2013/11/05/dragon-fruit-what-is-it-and-how-to-ea/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dragon fruit (Pitaya) is part of the cactus family, and has sweet, kiwi-like flesh. Dragon fruit is quite exotic for our latitudes and if your grocery store does not carry it, usually you can find this bright red skinned fruit, very rich in vitamins B and C as well as fiber, at your nearest Asian market. You can easily check if fruit is ripe by pressing on it, just like you’d choose ripe avocado, kiwi or peach. If it’s too soft that means it is overripe and the texture will not be as good. If it is too hard, you can still buy your dragon fruit but let it stay in cool dry place for few days to fully ripen. Any dry brown spots or dry spines on dragon fruit leathery skin are a sign to avoid it. There are more ideas what to do with dragon fruit: Dragon Fruit Jelly Mooncake Dragon Fruit Martini Pomegranate-Dragon Fruit Sorbet Dragon Fruit Jam]]></description>
		
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/11/dragon-fruit-what-is-it-and-how-to-eat.html/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
